<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://ririyad.github.io/rssreads/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-09-05T00:58:18.654Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ririyad.github.io/rssreads/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://ririyad.github.io/rssreads/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wanted: Skilled Workers To Combat the Rise in Cyber Crime]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/1955232/wanted-skilled-workers-to-combat-the-rise-in-cyber-crime?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/1955232/wanted-skilled-workers-to-combat-the-rise-in-cyber-crime?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T00:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a growing number of hackers target companies, organisations and industries with debilitating attacks, more skilled cyber security workers are urgently needed to combat the threat.ÂFrom a report: ISC2, the world's largest association of cyber professionals, estimates that the cyber security workforce in 2022 stood at about 4.7mn people globally. But a further 3.4mn roles remain unfilled. "The gap is massive," says Clar Rosso, ISC2's chief executive. "This shortfall is felt more acutely in countries such as India where digitisation is rapid. But even in the US, only 69 per cent of cyber roles are filled, according to Cyberseek, a website that provides data about the cyber security job market." 

Beyond a talent shortfall, existing workers are underskilled. A UK government report this year found that 50 per cent of UK businesses -- some 739,000 in total -- have a basic cyber skills gap, meaning that those in charge of cyber security lack the confidence to carry out the technical measures that protect against the most common digital attacks. Previously, it was thought that a company's IT team could take care of all cyber security concerns. But "over time, it became clear that this needed specialised attention," Rosso says, adding that, after some high-profile ransomware attacks over the past couple of years, "business executives are now paying attention."







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US Spy Agency Dreams of Surveillance Underwear]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/1950231/us-spy-agency-dreams-of-surveillance-underwear?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/1950231/us-spy-agency-dreams-of-surveillance-underwear?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The future of wearable technology, beyond now-standard accessories like smartwatches and fitness tracking rings, is ePANTS, according to the intelligence community. The Intercept: The federal government has shelled out at least $22 million in an effort to develop "smart" clothing that spies on the wearer and its surroundings. Similar to previous moonshot projects funded by military and intelligence agencies, the inspiration may have come from science fiction and superpowers, but the basic applications are on brand for the government: surveillance and data collection. Billed as the "largest single investment to develop Active Smart Textiles," the SMART ePANTS -- Smart Electrically Powered and Networked Textile Systems -- program aims to develop clothing capable of recording audio, video, and geolocation data, the Office of the Director of National Intelligence announced in an August 22 press release. Garments slated for production include shirts, pants, socks, and underwear, all of which are intended to be washable. 

The project is being undertaken by the Intelligence Advanced Research Projects Activity, the intelligence community's secretive counterpart to the military's better-known Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, or DARPA. IARPA's website says it "invests federal funding into high-risk, high reward projects to address challenges facing the intelligence community." Its tolerance for risk has led to both impressive achievements, like a Nobel Prize awarded to physicist David Wineland for his research on quantum computing funded by IARPA, as well as costly failures. "A lot of the IARPA and DARPA programs are like throwing spaghetti against the refrigerator," Annie Jacobsen, author of a book about DARPA, "The Pentagon's Brain," told The Intercept. "It may or may not stick."







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple and Microsoft Say Flagship Services Not Popular Enough To Be 'Gatekeepers']]></title>
        <id>https://apple.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/2030248/apple-and-microsoft-say-flagship-services-not-popular-enough-to-be-gatekeepers?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://apple.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/2030248/apple-and-microsoft-say-flagship-services-not-popular-enough-to-be-gatekeepers?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T20:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apple and Microsoft, the most valuable companies in the US, have argued some of their flagship services are insufficiently popular to be designated "gatekeepers" under landmark new EU legislation designed to curb the power of Big Tech. FT: Brussels' battle with Apple over its iMessage chat app and Microsoft's search engine Bing comes ahead of Wednesday's publication of the first list of services that will be regulated by the Digital Markets Act. The legislation imposes new responsibilities on the tech companies, including sharing data, linking to competitors and making their services interoperable with rival apps.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Y Combinator Removes Indian Startup From Batch Over 'Irregularities']]></title>
        <id>https://slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/1925258/y-combinator-removes-indian-startup-from-batch-over-irregularities?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/1925258/y-combinator-removes-indian-startup-from-batch-over-irregularities?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader shares a report: Storied venture firm Y Combinator has removed an Indian startup from its batch after discovering "irregularities" at the firm, several people familiar with the matter told TechCrunch. Medobed, an Indian startup that promises medicine delivery in 10 minutes, was initially selected in Y Combinator's S23 batch. In recent weeks, Y Combinator has severed its ties with the Indian firm and a partner at the venture firm has also suggested many prospective investors to not engage with Medobed, according to two people familiar with the matter and a copy of an email obtained by TechCrunch. It's very rare for Y Combinator, which selects a few hundred startups from tens of thousands of applications, to remove a firm from its coveted batch, the report adds.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canadian Prisons Restrict Technology To the 1990s]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/1854211/canadian-prisons-restrict-technology-to-the-1990s?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/1854211/canadian-prisons-restrict-technology-to-the-1990s?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[belmolis writes: Canadian prisons allow prisoners to buy devices such as personal computers and gaming consoles but severely restrict the technology, nominally on security grounds. Modern gaming consoles are forbidden on the grounds that they can connect to the internet, so the typical purchase is a Playstation 1. No version of Microsoft Windows more recent than Windows 98 is allowed. No device that can play MP3 files is allowed. The regulations forbid operating systems other than Microsoft DOS or Windows and any software capable of creating a program, such as a compiler as are "database programs capable of altering or manipulating SQL databases". Although learning job skills is encouraged, programming is evidently not considered appropriate. The relationship of most of these restrictions to security is obscure.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Billing 3 Cents a Minute To Revisit Tedious Teams Meetings via API]]></title>
        <id>https://slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/183201/microsoft-billing-3-cents-a-minute-to-revisit-tedious-teams-meetings-via-api?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/183201/microsoft-billing-3-cents-a-minute-to-revisit-tedious-teams-meetings-via-api?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T18:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft has announced billing in public preview for Teams recording and transcription APIs, with pricing starting at 3 cents per minute for recordings. From a report: Getting meeting transcripts and recordings using Graph APIs is currently in public developer preview, so the billing, which started on September 1, might irk coders keen to use these features in their applications. The API for recording is billed at $0.03 per minute, and the API for transcription is $0.024 per minute. 

Microsoft cited line-of-business applications or ISV solutions in sales or HR as potential use cases for the technology, which permits recordings as an MP4 video file or transcripts as VTT files to be downloaded. VTT includes handy information such as the spoken words, timings, language, and the names of the speakers. A developer could automatically generate notes and attach meeting clips using one or both content API sets. Other information, such as sentiment and engagement metrics, could also be generated.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU Prepares To Push For 'Global Phase-Out' of Fossil Fuels at COP28, Draft Document Shows]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/176220/eu-prepares-to-push-for-global-phase-out-of-fossil-fuels-at-cop28-draft-document-shows?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/176220/eu-prepares-to-push-for-global-phase-out-of-fossil-fuels-at-cop28-draft-document-shows?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T17:06:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A proposal to phase out CO2-emitting fossil fuels at COP27 last won backing from more than 80 countries but oil and gas-rich nations opposed it. European Union countries are preparing to push for a global deal on phasing out fossil fuels at the COP28 climate summit, a draft of the EU's negotiating position has shown. From a report: Diplomats from the bloc's 27 member states are drafting their position for the summit in Dubai in November, where nearly 200 countries will try to strengthen efforts to rein in climate change. "The shift towards a climate neutral economy will require the global phase-out of [unabated] fossil fuels and a peak in their consumption already in the near term," a draft of the EU's negotiating stance, seen by Reuters, says. 

Countries have never agreed in UN climate negotiations to gradually stop burning all CO2-emitting fossil fuels, despite this being the main cause of climate change. "Unabated" refers to fossil fuels burned without using technologies to capture the resulting CO2 emissions. The word was in brackets in the draft EU text, indicating that countries have not yet agreed on whether to include it. EU diplomats hope a deal can be made at COP28 - but expect to meet resistance from economies reliant on income from selling oil and gas.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Invasive Species Cost Humans $423 Billion Each Year and Threaten World's Diversity]]></title>
        <id>https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/1610205/invasive-species-cost-humans-423-billion-each-year-and-threaten-worlds-diversity?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/1610205/invasive-species-cost-humans-423-billion-each-year-and-threaten-worlds-diversity?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T16:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Invasive species are costing the world at least $423bn every year and have become a leading threat to the diversity of life on Earth, according to a UN assessment. From a news report: From invasive mice that eat seabird chicks in their nests to non-native grasses that helped fuel and intensify last month's deadly fires in Hawaii, at least 3,500 harmful invasive species have been recorded globally in every region, spread by human travel and trade. Their impact is destructive for humans and wildlife, sometimes causing extinctions and permanently damaging the healthy functioning of an ecosystem. 

Leading scientists say the threat posed by invasive species is under appreciated, underestimated and sometimes unacknowledged, with more than 37,000 alien species now known to be introduced around the world and about 200 establishing themselves each year. While not all will become invasive, experts say there are significant tools to mitigate their spread and impact, protecting and restoring ecosystems in the process. 

"Invasive alien species are a major threat to biodiversity and can cause irreversible damage to nature, including local and global species extinctions, and also threaten human wellbeing," wrote Prof Helen Roy, Prof Anibal Pauchard and Prof Peter Stoett, who led the research. "It would be an extremely costly mistake to regard biological invasions only as someone else's problem," said Pauchard. "Although the specific species that inflict damage vary from place to place, these are risks and challenges with global roots but very local impacts facing people in every country, from all backgrounds and in every community -- even Antarctica is being affected."







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LSE Group Draws Up Plans for Blockchain-based Digital Assets Business]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/154248/lse-group-draws-up-plans-for-blockchain-based-digital-assets-business?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/154248/lse-group-draws-up-plans-for-blockchain-based-digital-assets-business?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T15:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The London Stock Exchange Group has drawn up plans for a new digital markets business, saying this will make it the first major exchange to offer extensive trading of traditional financial assets on the blockchain technology best known for powering cryptocurrency. From a report: Murray Roos, head of capital's markets at the LSE Group, told the Financial Times that the company had been examining the potential for a blockchain-powered trading venue for about a year, and had reached an "inflection point" where it had decided to take the plans forward. It has asked Julia Hoggett, head of the London Stock Exchange, one unit in the broader group, to spearhead the project. 

Roos stressed that his exchange was "definitely not building anything around cryptoassets" but was looking to use the technology that underpins popular tokens such as bitcoin to improve the efficiency of buying, selling and holding traditional assets. "The idea is to use digital technology to make a process that is slicker, smoother, cheaper and more transparent and to have it regulated," Roos said. He added that LSEG had waited to proceed until it was sure that the public blockchain technology was "good enough" and that investors were ready.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Set To Embrace an iPhone Charger Change It Didn't Want]]></title>
        <id>https://apple.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/141243/apple-set-to-embrace-an-iphone-charger-change-it-didnt-want?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://apple.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/141243/apple-set-to-embrace-an-iphone-charger-change-it-didnt-want?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T14:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader shares a report: If Apple had its way, the iPhone would continue to use the current Lightning connector for the next few years -- until the point when the company is ready to begin phasing out ports on its smartphones altogether. But the European Union forced its hand, requiring mobile device makers to use the USB-C standard by the end of next year. So Apple is now in the awkward position of embracing the very technology it didn't want. When the company introduces the iPhone 15 on Sept. 12, USB-C connectors will appear on its four new phone models, as well as the AirPods Pro, and Apple will describe it as a major win for customers. 

Customers will be able to use a single charging cable for iPhones, Macs and iPads. It will bring breakthrough data transfer speed increases for the new high-end iPhone models. Phones will charge faster in some instances. And, finally, the phones will be compatible with chargers used by billions of non-Apple devices. 

Why will Apple be so upbeat about a change it didn't ask for? That's because the company has an iron-clad rule: When it's introducing a new product or dealing with the media, it always wants to operate from a position of strength. Apple's keynote presentation won't mention the European Union or make reference to the many times over the past few years that it criticized the government's decision to require USB-C. Back when it was still resisting the switch, Apple laid out a few arguments, including that the change would harm the environment -- given that billions of obsolete cables may wind up in a landfill. Another rationale, floated by Apple marketing chief Greg Joswiak last year, is the potentially harmful precedent of governments influencing product design.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Workers are Resisting Calls to Return to Offices]]></title>
        <id>https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/1528258/workers-are-resisting-calls-to-return-to-offices?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/1528258/workers-are-resisting-calls-to-return-to-offices?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T11:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[America's return-to-office has been a "lagging return," reports the Washington Post:

Even with millions of workers across the country being asked to return to their cubicles, office occupancy has been relatively static for the past year. The country's top 10 metropolitan areas averaged 47.2 percent of pre-pandemic levels last week, according to data from Kastle Systems. This time last year, the average was around 44 percent.... 

About 52 percent of remote-capable U.S. workers are operating under hybrid arrangements, according to data from Gallup, while 29 percent are exclusively remote. And though executives like Meta's Mark Zuckerberg have argued that the rise of flexible work has had a deleterious effect on productivity, data from the Bureau of Labor Statistics shows that labor product…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Self-Driving Cars Slowed Down in High-Tech Boston]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/0420246/why-self-driving-cars-slowed-down-in-high-tech-boston?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/0420246/why-self-driving-cars-slowed-down-in-high-tech-boston?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T08:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The city of Boston also allows testing of self-driving cars. But the Boston Globe reports that "There are far fewer complaints about self-driving cars because you barely see them."

[F]ollowing a string of high-profile crashes and the disruption of the COVID pandemic, the state Transportation Department — now under Governor Maura Healey — has seemingly lost its enthusiasm for AVs... Only one company is permitted to test autonomous vehicles here — Boston-based Motional — and it confines its occasional experiments to a corner of the Seaport and a closed track at Suffolk Downs in East Boston. And despite past efforts to woo autonomous-vehicle firms, the state hasn't received any new applications in years... 

Proponents have long said AVs could transform transportation, with all manner of eco…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scientists Finally Know Why Germany's Wild Boar Are Surprisingly Radioactive]]></title>
        <id>https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/0519225/scientists-finally-know-why-germanys-wild-boar-are-surprisingly-radioactive?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/0519225/scientists-finally-know-why-germanys-wild-boar-are-surprisingly-radioactive?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T05:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader shared this report from the Washington Post:

On April 26, 1986, the infamous explosion at a Chernobyl nuclear power plant unleashed large amounts of radiation into the atmosphere, an event that contaminated wildlife across country lines. The radiation levels seen in animals as a result has decreased in recent years — with the exception of one animal: the wild boar. For years, scientists questioned why levels of a radioactive isotope known as cesium-137 have remained surprisingly high in wild boars rooting around Germany and Austria, while decreasing in other deer and roe deer. In a new study released last week, a team of researchers finally solved this "wild boar paradox." 

They uncovered that the main radioactive source is not the Chernobyl accident but nuclear weapo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How a Billion-Dollar Satellite Risks Upending the Space Insurance Industry]]></title>
        <id>https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/0149214/how-a-billion-dollar-satellite-risks-upending-the-space-insurance-industry?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/09/04/0149214/how-a-billion-dollar-satellite-risks-upending-the-space-insurance-industry?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T01:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Viasat Inc. has more than $1 billion of orbiting satellites in trouble," reports Bloomberg, "and space insurers are girding for market-rattling claims."

The company's roughly $1 billion ViaSat-3 Americas satellite, central to expanding its fixed-broadband coverage and fending off rivals including Elon Musk's Starlink, suffered an unexpected problem as it deployed its antenna in orbit in April. Should Viasat declare it a total loss, industry executives estimate the claim would reach a record-breaking $420 million and, in turn, make it harder — and more expensive — for other satellite operators to get insurance... Viasat on Aug. 24 reported another stricken spacecraft, saying its Inmarsat-6 F2 satellite launched in February suffered a power problem. The failure may end the craft's useful life and result in a $350 million insurance claim, Space Intel Report said. 

Viasat's troubles in orbit come a few years after big-name insurers like American International Group Inc. and Allianz SE have shuttered their space portfolios. That's left a smaller pool of providers to absorb the risks in the notoriously high-stakes $553 million market... 


Following news of the Inmarsat-6 anomaly, Viasat and other industry participants "will likely experience significant challenges with obtaining insurance for future satellite launches," [investment banking firm] William Blair's Louie DiPalma said in an Aug. 25 note... In 2019, the total losses from satellite claims amounted to $788 million, which overwhelmed the total premiums for the year at $500 million, according to launch and satellite database Seradata. In the years that followed, big names like American International Group Inc., Swiss Re AG, and Allianz SE all closed the door on satellite insurance. 
Earlier this month Viasat's CEO says before deciding whether they'll file a claim, "There's no consequences to us taking another couple or three months to get good measurements and then making those decisions."







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping Rust projects secure with cargo-audit 0.18: performance, compatibility and security improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/09/04/keeping-secure-with-cargo-audit-0.18.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/09/04/keeping-secure-with-cargo-audit-0.18.html"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[cargo audit checks your project's dependencies for known security vulnerabilites.
By default cargo audit checks on your Cargo.lock file, but it can also scan compiled binaries. You can install cargo-audit and run it against your project with the following commands:
$ cargo install cargo-audit
$ cargo audit

Both cargo audit and the RustSec advisory database that powers it are maintained by the Rust Secure Code working group.
What's new in this release
Performance
cargo audit now uses the sparse crates.io index when checking for yanked crates. This dramatically speeds up the scanning process because cargo audit no longer needs to download the entire crates.io index, which could take up to several minutes.
Sparse index is used by default if you are running Rust 1.70 or later, same as in Carg…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Inside Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eight years of organizing tech meetups]]></title>
        <id>http://notes.eatonphil.com/eight-years-of-tech-meetups.html</id>
        <link href="http://notes.eatonphil.com/eight-years-of-tech-meetups.html"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a collection of random personal experiences. So if you don't
want to read everything, feel free to skip to the end for takeaways.
I write because I'd like to see more high-quality meetups. And maybe
my little bit of experience will help someone out.
2015: Philadelphia
I first tried to organize a meetup in Philly in 2015. I was
contracting at the time and I figured a meetup might be a good way to
source contracts or just meet interesting people. I created the
"Philadelphia Software in Business" (or some other similarly vaguely
named) group on Meetup.com.
I didn't have any network; the first companies I worked for were not
in Philly. But Meetup.com got me a few tens of people joining the
group.
My first challenge was finding a place to meet. I didn't know what I
was doing so I looked…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Notes on software development</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eight years of organizing tech meetups]]></title>
        <id>http://notes.eatonphil.com/eight-years-of-tech-meetups.html</id>
        <link href="http://notes.eatonphil.com/eight-years-of-tech-meetups.html"/>
        <updated>2023-09-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a collection of random personal experiences. So if you don't
want to read everything, feel free to skip to the end for takeaways.
I write because I'd like to see more high-quality meetups. And maybe
my little bit of experience will help someone out.
2015: Philadelphia
I first tried to organize a meetup in Philly in 2015. I was
contracting at the time and I figured a meetup might be a good way to
source contracts or just meet interesting people. I created the
"Philadelphia Software in Business" (or some other similarly vaguely
named) group on Meetup.com.
I didn't have any network; the first companies I worked for were not
in Philly. But Meetup.com got me a few tens of people joining the
group.
My first challenge was finding a place to meet. I didn't know what I
was doing so I looked…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Notes on software development</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[After Hurricane-Caused Flooding, Some EVs Exposed To Saltwater Caught Fire]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/2248249/after-hurricane-caused-flooding-some-evs-exposed-to-saltwater-caught-fire?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/2248249/after-hurricane-caused-flooding-some-evs-exposed-to-saltwater-caught-fire?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-03T22:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CBS News reports:
Floridians battered by Hurricane Idalia this week may not have expected another threat — that floodwaters could cause their cars to suddenly burst into flames. Yet that's exactly what happened when two electric vehicles caught fire after being submerged in saltwater churned up by the storm... 

"If you own a hybrid or electric vehicle that has come into contact with saltwater due to recent flooding within the last 24 hours, it is crucial to relocate the vehicle from your garage without delay," the fire department said in a Facebook post. "Saltwater exposure can trigger combustion in lithium-ion batteries. If possible, transfer your vehicle to higher ground." The warning also applies to electric golf carts, scooters and bicycles, with lithium-ion batteries potentially sparking a fire when they get wet. More specifically, salt residue remains after the water dries out and can create "bridges" between the battery's cells, potentially creating electrical connections that can spark a fire. 
Fire crews were actually towing one of the vehicles when it burst into flames, the article points out. And EV manufacturers want people to take the possibility seriously:

Tesla warns car owners about the risks of vehicle submersion and advises against driving a car that has been flooded. "Treat your vehicle as if it has been in an accident and contact your insurance company," the company says in its guidance for handling a submerged vehicle.
 
Thanks to long-time Slashdot reader schwit1 for sharing the article.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gannett Halts AI-Written Sports Recaps After Readers Mocked the Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/200248/gannett-halts-ai-written-sports-recaps-after-readers-mocked-the-stories?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/200248/gannett-halts-ai-written-sports-recaps-after-readers-mocked-the-stories?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-03T20:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CNN reports that newspaper chain Gannett "has paused the use of an AI tool to write high school sports dispatches after the technology made several major flubs in articles in at least one of its papers."
In one notable example, preserved by the Internet Archive's Wayback Machine, the story began: "The Worthington Christian [[WINNING_TEAM_MASCOT]] defeated the Westerville North [[LOSING_TEAM_MASCOT]] 2-1 in an Ohio boys soccer game on Saturday...." The reports were mocked on social media for being repetitive, lacking key details, using odd language and generally sounding like they'd been written by a computer with no actual knowledge of sports. 

CNN identified several other local Gannett outlets, including the Louisville Courrier Journal, AZ Central, Florida Today and the Milwaukee Journal…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[China Accused of 'Coordinated Disinformation Campaign' About Fukushima Waste Water in Multiple Countries]]></title>
        <id>https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/196247/china-accused-of-coordinated-disinformation-campaign-about-fukushima-waste-water-in-multiple-countries?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/196247/china-accused-of-coordinated-disinformation-campaign-about-fukushima-waste-water-in-multiple-countries?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-03T19:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BBC has an article about Japan's release into the sea of treated waste water from the damaged Fukushima nuclear plant. "Scientists largely agree that the impact will be negligible, but China has strongly protested the release. And disinformation has only fuelled fear and suspicion in China."

A report by a UK-based data analysis company called Logically, which aims to fight misinformation, claims that since January, the Chinese government and state media have been running a coordinated disinformation campaign targeting the release of the waste water. As part of this, mainstream news outlets in China have continually questioned the science behind the nuclear waste water discharge. The rhetoric has only increased since the water was released on 24 August, stoking public anger... Japan's foreign ministry even warned its citizens in China to be cautious and to avoid speaking Japanese loudly in public... 

Logically's data also showed that, since the beginning of the year, state-owned media have run paid ads on Facebook and Instagram, without disclaimers, about the risks of the waste water release in multiple countries and languages, including English, German, and Khmer. "It is quite evident that this is politically motivated," Hamsini Hariharan, a China expert at Logically, told the BBC. She added that misleading content from sources related to the Chinese government had intensified the public outcry... 

Dozens of posts on Chinese social media Weibo showed panicked crowds buying giant sacks of salt ahead of the Fukushima water release. Some worried that future supply would be contaminated. Others believed — falsely — that salt protected them against radiation. A restaurant in Shanghai, in an apparent effort to profit off the hysteria, advertised "anti-radiation" meals with errant claims of reducing skin damage and cell regeneration. A social media user asked wryly, "Why would I pay 28 yuan for tomato with seasoning?"







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Silicon Valley Billionaires Reveal First Renderings for Planned City in California]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/1841241/silicon-valley-billionaires-reveal-first-renderings-for-planned-city-in-california?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/1841241/silicon-valley-billionaires-reveal-first-renderings-for-planned-city-in-california?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-03T18:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Silicon Valley billionaires behind a secretive $800 million land-buying spree in Northern California have finally released some details about their plans for a new green city," reports the Associated Press, "but they still must win over skeptical voters and local leaders."
After years of ducking scrutiny, Jan Sramek, the former Goldman Sachs trader spearheading the effort, launched a website Thursday about "California Forever." The site billed the project as "a chance for a new community, good paying local jobs, solar farms, and open space" in Solano, a rural county between San Francisco and Sacramento that is now home to 450,000 people. He also began meeting with key politicians representing the area who have been trying unsuccessfully for years to find out who was behind the mysterious …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cruise Disputes Report Its Robotaxi Blocked an Ambulance Carrying Patient Who Later Died]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/1722242/cruise-disputes-report-its-robotaxi-blocked-an-ambulance-carrying-patient-who-later-died?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/1722242/cruise-disputes-report-its-robotaxi-blocked-an-ambulance-carrying-patient-who-later-died?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-03T17:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Two stalled driverless taxis blocked an ambulance carrying a critically injured patient," writes the San Francisco Chronicle, citing a paywalled report from Forbes. The delay "contributed to 'poor patient outcome' — the person died 20 to 30 minutes after reaching the hospital, according to a report by San Francisco firefighters that the taxi company disputes." 

The report was obtained by Forbes, which recently published a story detailing accounts by San Francisco firefighters who say driverless taxis have repeatedly interfered with their emergency response. However, Forbes also reported that Cruise provided a video that disputed SFFD's account of the August 14 incident. The video, Forbes reported, shows that one Cruise car quickly left the scene while the other remained stalled at the intersection with an open lane to its right, which traffic was passing through. Forbes said it was not clear from the video if the ambulance could have navigated into the open lane. 

Hannah Lindow, a Cruise spokesperson, told the Chronicle that the Cruise vehicle that stopped did so to yield to first responders directing traffic. "Throughout the entire duration the (autonomous vehicle) is stopped, traffic remains unblocked and flowing to the right of the AV. The ambulance behind the AV had a clear path to pass the AV as other vehicles, including another ambulance, proceeded to do," Lindow said in an email. "As soon as the victim was loaded into the ambulance, the ambulance left the scene immediately and was never impeded from doing so by the AV."







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mission Accomplished, India Puts Moon Rover to 'Sleep' for 14 Days]]></title>
        <id>https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/1622210/mission-accomplished-india-puts-moon-rover-to-sleep-for-14-days?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/1622210/mission-accomplished-india-puts-moon-rover-to-sleep-for-14-days?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-03T16:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To complete one full rotation around its axis it takes the moon 655 hours. So a single "lunar day" is 13.64 earth days. 

But sunset has finally come for India's Chandrayaan-3 spacecraft and its Pragyan rover, writes long-time Slashdot reader Geoffrey.landis , and the rover has switched off for the coming 655-hour night:
With luck from the moon gods, it will wake up with the sunrise in 14 days. But, even if not, mission accomplished! It was designed for fourteen days of operation, the daylight period. In that time the rover accomplished just over a hundred meters (American units: one football field) of traverse, examining and chemically analyzing the surface. 


"The Indian Express newspaper said the electronics on board the Indian moon mission werenâ(TM)t designed to withstand very low temperatures, less than -120 C (-184 F) during the nighttime on the moon," according to the Associated Press. But the rover's accomplishments already include making the first-ever measurements of the south pole's near-surface Lunar plasma, and confirming the presence of aluminum, calcium, chromium, titanium, manganese, and silicon. There's also sulphur, iron, oxygen and other elements on the moon, Reuters reports, citing a statement from the Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO):

The Pragyan rover from the Chandrayaan-3 spacecraft was "set into Sleep mode" but with batteries charged and receiver on, the ISRO said in a post on X, formerly Twitter, late on Saturday. "Hoping for a successful awakening for another set of assignments!" ISRO said. "Else, it will forever stay there as India's lunar ambassador." 



Earlier this week the ISRO posted footage of the rover completing a near-pirouette to search for the safest route. 

"The solar panel is oriented to receive the light at the next sunrise expected on September 22, 2023," the ISRO posted Saturday.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[After 28 Years, Microsoft Announces it Will Remove WordPad From Windows]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/0050200/after-28-years-microsoft-announces-it-will-remove-wordpad-from-windows?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/0050200/after-28-years-microsoft-announces-it-will-remove-wordpad-from-windows?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-03T15:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Microsoft has quietly revealed that WordPad, the basic word processor that's been included with Windows since 1995, is being retired," reports Windows blog Paul Thurrott:
"WordPad is no longer being updated and will be removed in a future release of Windows," the Deprecated features for Windows client page on Microsoft Learn notes in a September 1, 2023 addition. "We recommend Microsoft Word for rich text documents like .doc and .rtf and Windows Notepad for plain text documents like .txt...." 

[W]hile Microsoft's advice to use Microsoft Word instead seems a bit off-base, given that Word is a paid product, RTF is rarely used these days, and anyone can access the web versions of Word for free if needed. 

The actual date of removal is unclear. But Neowinisn't the only thing Microsoft is removing from Windows:
The company recently turned off Cortana, its neglected voice assistant, and announced the end of Microsoft Support Diagnostic Tool (MSDT). Also, Microsoft will soon disable old Transport Layer Security protocols to make Windows 11 more secure.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux's Marketshare on Steam Still Higher Than Apple macOS]]></title>
        <id>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/001201/linuxs-marketshare-on-steam-still-higher-than-apple-macos?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/23/09/03/001201/linuxs-marketshare-on-steam-still-higher-than-apple-macos?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-03T14:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The (Arch Linux-powered) Steam Deck was released in February of 2022 — and Phoronix reports that's helping Linux's market share on Steam. "While July was at 1.96% for Linux, the August numbers [from SteamPowered.com] show a 0.14% dip to 1.82%.

Interestingly, macOS dipped by 0.27% to 1.57% while Windows rose by 0.4% to 96.61%. For those wondering why the Steam Linux numbers dropped while the Steam Deck continues to be very popular, it's possibly again another month impacted by large swings in Chinese traffic... SteamOS Holo that powers the Steam Deck gained another 2% marketshare to now commanding around 44% of the reported Linux gamers. 

Among Linux gamers, AMD CPUs power around 71% of the systems. In part due to the Steam Deck being powered by an AMD APU. Meanwhile Steam on Windows has the AMD CPU marketshare at around 33%.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Titan Submersible Disaster Was Years In the Making, New Details Reveal]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1853216/the-titan-submersible-disaster-was-years-in-the-making-new-details-reveal?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1853216/the-titan-submersible-disaster-was-years-in-the-making-new-details-reveal?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-03T11:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vanity Fair revisits the many warning signs about OceanGate's Titan submersible prior to an implosion on June 18th that killed all five passengers onboard. 


A professional expedition leader tells their reporter that "This tragedy was predicted. It was avoidable. It was inevitable."

As the world now knows, Stockton Rush touted himself as a maverick, a disrupter, a breaker of rules. So far out on the visionary curve that, for him, safety regulations were mere suggestions. "If you're not breaking things, you're not innovating," he declared at the 2022 GeekWire Summit. "If you're operating within a known environment, as most submersible manufacturers do, they don't break things. To me, the more stuff you've broken, the more innovative you've been." In a culture that has adopted the ridiculo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Scrums a Cancer?]]></title>
        <id>https://developers.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1753239/are-scrums-a-cancer?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://developers.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1753239/are-scrums-a-cancer?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-03T07:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Santiago Valdarrama teaches machine learning. He posted this week on Twitter and LinkedIn that "Scrum is a cancer." Some highlights:
I've been writing software for 25 years, and nothing renders a software team useless like Scrum does... We spent more time talking than doing... We spent more time estimating story points than writing software... Imagine having a manager, a scrum master, a product owner, and a tech lead. You had to answer to all of them and none simultaneously... 

I believe in Agile, but this ain't agile... The result was always the same: It didn't work. Scrum is a cancer that will eat your development team. Scrum is not for developers; it's another tool for managers to feel they are in control. 

DevOps.com shares some reactions, including the developer who calls Scrum "a life-sucking batch of meetings that are good for one thing: Taking developers who can't or don't want to see the overall business/architecture picture and getting useful work out of them." 

But later in the week, Valdarrama revisited the issue with a follow-up post. "After 3,400 replies, I learned a few things."
First, the most common jobs among the people who told me I was wrong were "Agile Coach" and "Scrum Master...." 
Second, Scrum can't fail because Scrum is whatever you want Scrum to be. There's no right way to do Scrum, so if it doesn't work for you, you aren't as bright as you thought you were. 

Third, Scrum isn't agile, except when it is. But it's much better than Waterfall, except when it isn't. And it's better than nothing and everything at the same time. 

Fourth, many people got triggered by my comparison of Scrum and communism... 

Finally, by far, most people hate Scrum with passion. 

Thanks to Slashdot reader RUs1729 for sharing the link.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ignored by Police, Two Women Took Down Their Cyber-Harasser Themselves]]></title>
        <id>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/2217216/ignored-by-police-two-women-took-down-their-cyber-harasser-themselves?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/2217216/ignored-by-police-two-women-took-down-their-cyber-harasser-themselves?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-03T04:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's how the Washington Post tells the story of 34-year-old marketer (and former model) Madison Conradis, who discovered nude behind-the-scenes photos from 10 years earlier had leaked after a series of photographer web sites were breached:
Now the photos along with her name and contact information were on 4chan, a lawless website that allows users to post anonymously about topics as varied as music and white supremacy... Facebook users registered under fake names such as "Joe Bummer" sent her direct messages demanding that she send new, explicit photos, or else they would further spread the already leaked photos. Some pictures landed in her father's Instagram messages, while marketing clients told her about the nude images that came their way. Madison was at a friend's party when she got…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Exit: Rains Close the Roads In and Out of Burning Man]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/2316227/no-exit-rains-close-the-roads-in-and-out-of-burning-man?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/2316227/no-exit-rains-close-the-roads-in-and-out-of-burning-man?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-03T00:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Though it's Saturday at Nevada's desert-based Burning Man event "Dawn brought a growing realization for attendees that they might not be going home as planned, given rain forecast for later Saturday into Sunday..." reports the Reno Gazette-Journal. "More than 73,000 Burning Man attendees remain confined to their camps Saturday and are blocked from leaving the event after a slow-moving rainstorm turned their desert playground into a soupy, muddy morass." 

Burning Man has now closed both its entrance and exits gates. "Organizers warned attendees to conserve their food and water, indicating the closures could be lengthy."

There was no estimated time for reopening, and thousands of attendees are facing the potential of missing flights, failing to return rental cars or failing to return to wo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switching out git remotes]]></title>
        <id>https://dietcode.io/t/fork-remote/</id>
        <link href="https://dietcode.io/t/fork-remote/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Miscellaneous git knowledge that may be helpful when hacking on OSS repositories]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dietcode | Sid's blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ask Slashdot:  Do Streamers Waste More Time Deciding What to Watch?]]></title>
        <id>https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1625219/ask-slashdot-do-streamers-waste-more-time-deciding-what-to-watch?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1625219/ask-slashdot-do-streamers-waste-more-time-deciding-what-to-watch?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T22:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Are you old enough to remember channel surfing?" asks long-time Slashdog reader MightyMait. "When there were only a handful of broadcast channels, it wasn't a big deal..."

But when we got cable/satelite, one could spend inordinate amounts of time flipping through the channels looking for something decent to watch. Now, with the proliferation of streaming services... 

Streaming viewers are now "spending a record 10.5 minutes per session deciding what to watch," according to TV Tech, citing a new study from the Nielsen-owned entertainment-data company Gracenote. 

Their 2023 State of Play report "found that that there were 1.9 million video titles available to viewers in the U.S., U.K., Canada, Mexico and Germany in July 2021, a number that had swelled to 2.7 million titles by June 2023."
Of the total count, a whopping 86.7% were available on streaming services. Compounding complexity, many popular shows now appear in multiple streaming catalogs, as the industry pivots from offering content exclusivity to broad distribution strategies that companies hope will balance massive streaming loses, the report noted. The Gracenote analysis also found that audiences now have nearly 40,000 individual FAST channels, streaming providers and aggregators to choose from. 

The original submission from MightyMait asks Slashdot readers: "Are you feeling the pain? And if so, "What strategies do you employ to avoid this time suck?" 
Share your own thoughts and experiences in the comments. And do streamers spend more time deciding what to watch?







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ArcaOS 5.1.0 (OEM OS/2 Warp Operating System) Now Available]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1912223/arcaos-510-oem-os2-warp-operating-system-now-available?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1912223/arcaos-510-oem-os2-warp-operating-system-now-available?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T21:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Slashdot reader martiniturbide writes: ArcaOS 5.1.0 is an OEM distribution of IBM's discontinued OS/2 Warp operating system. This new version of ArcaOS offers UEFI compatibility allowing it to run in modern x86 hardware and also includes the ability to install to GPT-based disk layouts. 

At OS2World the OS/2 community has been called upon to report supported hardware, open source any OS/2 software, make public as much OS/2 documentation as possible and post the important platform links. OS2World insists that open source has helped OS/2 in the past years and it is time to look under the hood to try to clone internal components like Control Program, Presentation Manager, SOM and Workplace Shell.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[America's IRS Can't Find Millions of Sensitive Tax Records: Watchdog]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/184245/americas-irs-cant-find-millions-of-sensitive-tax-records-watchdog?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/184245/americas-irs-cant-find-millions-of-sensitive-tax-records-watchdog?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T20:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader shares The Hill's report from earlier this month. Apparently America's tax-collecting Internal Revenue Service "cannot locate thousands of microfilm cartridges containing millions of sensitive individual and business tax account records, according to a watchdog report."

The Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration said in a report released August 8 that the IRS cannot account for microfilm cartridges — which contain backups of tax records as required under federal law — from fiscal 2010 that were originally stored at a processing center in Fresno, California... The watchdog also found seven empty boxes, which could hold up to 168 cartridges total, at the Ogden Tax Processing Center in Utah. Ogden personnel did not know where the missing cartridges were. 

More than 4,000 cartridges containing business tax account information from fiscal 2018 and 4,500 cartridges containing individual tax account information from fiscal 2019 also could not be accounted for at the Kansas City facility, according to the report. 

"The personal taxpayer and tax information included on these backup cartridges is key information that can be used to commit tax refund fraud identity theft," the report noted.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple's IPads-for-Concealed-Firearms-Licenses Bribery Case Moves Forward]]></title>
        <id>https://apple.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1722245/apples-ipads-for-concealed-firearms-licenses-bribery-case-moves-forward?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://apple.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1722245/apples-ipads-for-concealed-firearms-licenses-bribery-case-moves-forward?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T19:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Generally you may not carry a concealed firearm on your person in public," warns a California government web site, "unless you have a valid Carry Concealed Weapon (CCW) license." And a California appellate court associated justice writes that in the county where Apple is located, "the Santa Clara County Sheriff's Office rarely issued CCW licenses." 

This has led to Thomas Moyer, Apple's head of global security, facing bribery charges, reports Reason's legal blog, the Volokh Conspiracy. According to the judge's statement (citing the case of the public defender)...

...the Santa Clara County undersheriff requested — and defendant Thomas Moyer made — a promise to donate iPads to the Santa Clara County Sheriff's Office in exchange for releasing concealed carry weapon licenses that the sheriff had signed. Consistent with the Ninth Circuit's interpretation of California law, federal law and the law in many states, we conclude that such a promise may constitute a bribe. We also conclude that the evidence presented to the grand jury was sufficient to raise a reasonable suspicion of such bribery. Accordingly, we reverse the trial court's order dismissing the bribery count against Moyer, reinstate that count, and remand for further proceedings.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[French Error Blamed for UK's Air Control Meltdown Which Left 300,000 Passengers With Cancellations]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1651243/french-error-blamed-for-uks-air-control-meltdown-which-left-300000-passengers-with-cancellations?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1651243/french-error-blamed-for-uks-air-control-meltdown-which-left-300000-passengers-with-cancellations?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T18:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What caused Monday's glitch in the UK's air traffic control system that left thousands of passengers stranded? 

Wednesday the Independent reported that it may have been triggered by "an incorrectly filed flight plan by a French airline."

Several sources say the issue may have been caused when a French airline filed a dodgy flight plan that made no digital sense. Instead of the error being rejected, it prompted a shutdown of the entire National Air Traffic Services (Nats) system — raising questions over how one clerical error could cause such mayhem... Downing Street has launched an independent review into the incident, which caused more than a quarter of flights at UK airports to be cancelled on Monday... 

In his statement, Nats chief executive Martin Rolfe said Nats' systems, both primary and the back-ups, responded to the incorrect flight data by suspending automatic processing "to ensure that no incorrect safety-related information could be presented to an air traffic controller or impact the rest of the air traffic system". 

The article also points out that "Passengers hit by the air traffic control meltdown face being stranded abroad for up to a week."

Around 300,000 airline passengers have now been hit by flight cancellations since the hours-long failure of the Nats system on bank holiday Monday. The knock-on effect is set to last for several more days, as under-pressure airlines battle the backlog in a week where millions are already returning to the UK from their summer holidays. 
Thanks to Slashdot reader Bruce66423 for sharing the article.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Does Nuclear Get In the Way of Renewable? France and Germany Disagree.]]></title>
        <id>https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1453238/does-nuclear-get-in-the-way-of-renewable-france-and-germany-disagree?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1453238/does-nuclear-get-in-the-way-of-renewable-france-and-germany-disagree?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T17:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["France and Germany lead the camps in disagreeing on the future of nuclear in Europe," write two climate policy journalists. On the Energy Post blog they explore why — citing energy experts and politicians. 

Germany "ultimately completed its nuclear exit in April 2023," while France "has the highest share of nuclear in the energy mix of any country in the world."


[A] major concern is that more nuclear means less renewables, at a time when wind and solar need all the scale they can get... In a joint attempt to provide greater technical clarity on the nuclear power debate, French think tank IDDRI and German Agora Energiewende set out in 2018 to understand how nuclear energy will influence the transformation of energy systems in both countries. They found that if a high share of coal or nu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Are GoDaddy's<nobr> <wbr></nobr>.US Domains Being Used For So Much Phishing?]]></title>
        <id>https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1415234/why-are-godaddys-us-domains-being-used-for-so-much-phishing?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/1415234/why-are-godaddys-us-domains-being-used-for-so-much-phishing?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T16:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader shared this report from cybersecurity blogger Brian Krebs:

Domain names ending in ".US" — the top-level domain for the United States — are among the most prevalent in phishing scams, new research shows. This is noteworthy because .US is overseen by the U.S. government, which is frequently the target of phishing domains ending in .US. Also, .US domains are only supposed to be available to U.S. citizens and to those who can demonstrate that they have a physical presence in the United States... [F]ew other major countries in the world have anywhere near as many phishing domains each year as .US. 

That's according to The Interisle Consulting Group, which gathers phishing data from multiple industry sources and publishes an annual report on the latest trends. Interisle's newest study examined six million phishing reports between May 1, 2022 and April 30, 2023, and found 30,000 .US phishing domains. 

.US is overseen by the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA), an executive branch agency of the U.S. Department of Commerce. However, NTIA currently contracts out the management of the .US domain to GoDaddy, by far the world's largest domain registrar. Under NTIA regulations, the administrator of the .US registry must take certain steps to verify that their customers actually reside in the United States, or own organizations based in the U.S. But Interisle found that whatever GoDaddy was doing to manage that vetting process wasn't working.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are We Seeing the End of the Googleverse?]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/0557232/are-we-seeing-the-end-of-the-googleverse?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/0557232/are-we-seeing-the-end-of-the-googleverse?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T15:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Verge argues we're seeing "the end of the Googleverse. For two decades, Google Search was the invisible force that determined the ebb and flow of online content. 

"Now, for the first time, its cultural relevance is in question... all around us are signs that the era of 'peak Google' is ending or, possibly, already over."

There is a growing chorus of complaints that Google is not as accurate, as competent, as dedicated to search as it once was. The rise of massive closed algorithmic social networks like Meta's Facebook and Instagram began eating the web in the 2010s. 	More recently, there's been a shift to entertainment-based video feeds like TikTok — which is now being used as a primary search engine by a new generation of internet users... 

Google Reader shut down in 2013, taking w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Starfield' Fan Banned From Subreddit For Narcing On Leaker To Cops]]></title>
        <id>https://games.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/0536233/starfield-fan-banned-from-subreddit-for-narcing-on-leaker-to-cops?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://games.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/0536233/starfield-fan-banned-from-subreddit-for-narcing-on-leaker-to-cops?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T14:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kotaku reports that last week 29-year old Darin Harris "allegedly stole dozens of copies of the game from a warehouse and started selling them online," prompting lots of pre-release leaks for the game. 

"One Reddit user immediately reported the leaks to Bethesda and Memphis police," adds Kotaku. "And he's now been banned from the r/GamingLeaksAndRumours subreddit after posting about it."

I know this because the commenter in question, Jasper Adkins, emailed Kotaku to inform us it had happened. "It seems to me that the subreddit is running on 'bread and circuses' mode mixed with bystander syndrome," he wrote in his initial email. "They're perfectly willing to ignore a crime that hurts a developer they claim to support, in exchange for a few minutes of shaky gameplay filmed from a phone....…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Biotech Company Says It Put Dopamine-Making Cells Into People's Brains]]></title>
        <id>https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/0150234/a-biotech-company-says-it-put-dopamine-making-cells-into-peoples-brains?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/0150234/a-biotech-company-says-it-put-dopamine-making-cells-into-peoples-brains?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A biotech company has conducted a small-scale trial involving the implantation of lab-made neurons into the brains of 12 people with Parkinson's disease. The implanted neurons are designed to produce dopamine, which is deficient in Parkinson's patients, and early data suggests they may have survived and improved symptoms in some cases. MIT Technology Review reports: The study is one of the largest and most costly tests yet of embryonic-stem-cell technology, the controversial and much-hyped approach of using stem cells taken from IVF embryos to produce replacement tissue and body parts. The replacement neurons were manufactured using powerful stem cells originally sourced from a human embryo created an in vitro fertilization procedure. According to data presented by Henchliffe and others on…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pentagon's New UFO Website Lets You Explore Declassified Sightings Info]]></title>
        <id>https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/0017225/pentagons-new-ufo-website-lets-you-explore-declassified-sightings-info?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/0017225/pentagons-new-ufo-website-lets-you-explore-declassified-sightings-info?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The U.S. Department of Defense has launched a website collecting publicly available, declassified information on unidentified anomalous phenomena (UAPs). "For now, the general public will be able to read through the posted information," reports CNET. "Soon, US government employees, contractors, and service members with knowledge of US programs can report their own sightings, and later, others will be able to submit reports." From the report: "This website will provide information, including photos and videos, on resolved UAP cases as they are declassified and approved for public release," the department said in a release posted on Thursday. "The website's other content includes reporting trends and a frequently asked questions section as well as links to official reports, transcripts, press releases, and other resources that the public may find useful, such as applicable statutes and aircraft, balloon and satellite tracking sites."
 
For now, one of the most interesting parts of the site is its trends section. Apparently, most reported UAPs are round, either white, silver or translucent, spotted at around 10,000 to 30,000 feet, 1-4 meters in size, and do not emit thermal exhaust. Hotspots for sightings include both the US East and West coasts. There's also a small section of videos with names such as "DVIDS Video - Unresolved Case: Navy 2021 Flyby," and "UAP Video: Middle East Object." Readers are able to leave comments on the videos. Of the "Middle East Object" video, one person writes,"Noticed I never saw it cast a shadow. But other objects have shadows."







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Population Collapse Almost Wiped Out Human Ancestors, Say Scientists]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/0010246/population-collapse-almost-wiped-out-human-ancestors-say-scientists?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/0010246/population-collapse-almost-wiped-out-human-ancestors-say-scientists?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T03:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader quotes a report from The Guardian: Early human ancestors came close to eradication in a severe evolutionary bottleneck between 800,000 and 900,000 years ago, according to scientists. A genomics analysis of more than 3,000 living people suggested that our ancestors' total population plummeted to about 1,280 breeding individuals for about 117,000 years. Scientists believe that an extreme climate event could have led to the bottleneck that came close to wiping out our ancestral line. "The numbers that emerge from our study correspond to those of species that are currently at risk of extinction," said Prof Giorgio Manzi, an anthropologist at Sapienza University of Rome and a senior author of the research. However, Manzi and his colleagues believe that the existential pressu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NYPD To Deploy Drones To Monitor Backyard Parties This Holiday Weekend]]></title>
        <id>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/000207/nypd-to-deploy-drones-to-monitor-backyard-parties-this-holiday-weekend?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/09/02/000207/nypd-to-deploy-drones-to-monitor-backyard-parties-this-holiday-weekend?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T02:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["The NYC police department intends to use drones to monitor Labor Day backyard parties, raising privacy concerns," writes Slashdot reader jjslash. "Drone usage by U.S. police departments is increasing, with some operating them beyond visual line of sight. TechSpot reports: "If a caller states there's a large crowd, a large party in a backyard, we're going to be utilizing our assets to go up and go check on the party," said assistant NYPD Commissioner Kaz Daughtry at a recent press conference. Naturally, the admission attracted the attention of privacy and civil liberties advocates who questioned if the department's plans violate existing laws governing surveillance in the area.
 
In its unmanned aircraft systems (UAS): Impact and use policy from 2021, the NYC police department said drones would not be used in areas where there is a reasonable expectation of privacy without a search warrant, except in exigent circumstances (PDF). Are backyard parties really all that pressing? "Deploying drones in this way is a sci-fi inspired scenario," said Daniel Schwarz, a technology and privacy strategist with the New York Civil Liberties Union. Schwarz added that it is at variance with the Public Oversight of Surveillance Technology (POST) Act, which "requires the reporting and evaluation of surveillance technologies used by the NYPD."







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Patents Sensor-Filled, AI-Assisted Backpack]]></title>
        <id>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/2315228/microsoft-patents-sensor-filled-ai-assisted-backpack?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/2315228/microsoft-patents-sensor-filled-ai-assisted-backpack?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T01:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft has patented an AI-powered backpack design featuring a plethora of sensors that may include cameras, microphones, GPS, and a compass. Tom's Hardware reports: Additionally, Microsoft thinks it may be useful to add in LEDs and speakers, as well as a haptic actuator, into the straps. Some real-time processing is deemed necessary to the smart wearable. Thus, various recognition modules are proposed to provide image, text, speech, facial, and cognitive recognition. As well as real-time monitors feeding data to the built-in processing power for AI smarts, the system housed in the backpack also will boast a recording device (using on-board storage), wireless connectivity, battery power / charging and more.
 
With all the above sensing and processing on your person, in the backpack, it is envisioned that wearers will benefit from AI enhanced object identification and analysis, nearby device interaction, and be able to gain contextual insights. A flow chart shows how the backpack and its data feed might work alongside personal computers and cloud servers. Other illustrations show the wandering backpack wearer navigating a ski resort, and checking out supermarket prices, as well as considering booking concert tickets. Sometimes the user may interact with the backpack's on-board AI via speech, e.g. "Hey Backpack, add this poster to my calendar." Alternatively some AI actions or contextual tasks may be instigated by interacting with sensors on the straps. You can view the patent application here.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CalTech To Accept Khan Academy Success As Option For Admission]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/237204/caltech-to-accept-khan-academy-success-as-option-for-admission?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/237204/caltech-to-accept-khan-academy-success-as-option-for-admission?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T00:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Given that too many schools don't teach calculus, chemistry and physics, CalTech is allowing potential undergraduates to demonstrate their ability in these fields by using Khan Academy," writes Slashdot reader Bruce66423. Los Angeles Times reports: One of Caltech's alternative paths is taking Khan Academy's free, online classes and scoring 90% or higher on a certification test. Sal Khan, academy founder, said Caltech's action is a "huge deal" for equitable access to college. While Caltech is small -- only 2,400 students, about 40% of them undergraduates -- Khan said he hoped its prestigious reputation would encourage other institutions to examine their admission barriers and find creative solutions to ease them. The Pasadena-based institute, with a 3% admission rate last year, boasts 46 N…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nissan Begins Repurposing Leaf Car Batteries As Portable Power Stations]]></title>
        <id>https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/2246211/nissan-begins-repurposing-leaf-car-batteries-as-portable-power-stations?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/2246211/nissan-begins-repurposing-leaf-car-batteries-as-portable-power-stations?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-02T00:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader quotes a report from ExtremeTech: Slowly but surely, sales of electric cars have crept upward as traditional automakers finally embrace EVs. Nissan was early to the electric future with the venerable if modest Leaf. Nissan is now looking to turn old Leafs into something new by harvesting their batteries. The company has begun selling portable power banks built around refurbished automotive batteries, which could give these expensive Leaf cells a new lease on life. The Lithium-ion cells in vehicles have the same properties as the battery in your phone. They start out with a specific power rating, but successive discharge-recharge cycles cause physical stress to the internal structure. Eventually, this results in reduced capacity and voltage. However, Nissan says most Leaf owners stop driving the car before the battery stops working. In fact, many of the individual cells are still in good shape when the vehicles are discarded.
 
Each Nissan Leaf has around 48 lithium-ion battery modules -- the exact number depends on model. While some may be in poor shape at the end of a car's life, Nissan has taken to disassembling the battery packs to refurbish working modules. The result is the Nissan portable power station, which was developed in partnership with JVCKenwood Corp. and 4R Energy Corp. The bulky 32-pound portable chargers contain two Leaf battery modules with about 80% of their original capacity intact. They're no longer suitable for driving an EV, but they can still charge your phone. Nissan sells the battery packs in Japan for 170,500 yen (about $1,170). That might sound like a lot, but it's actually not bad for a super high-capacity battery pack. Each of Nissan's current-gen battery modules is 1.67 kWh, which converts to 112 Ah (112,000 mAh). Assuming a 20% loss in capacity, two of them would have enough juice to charge the largest current iPhone more than 40 times.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lenovo's New 27-inch, 4K Monitor Offers Glasses-Free 3D]]></title>
        <id>https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/2239233/lenovos-new-27-inch-4k-monitor-offers-glasses-free-3d?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/2239233/lenovos-new-27-inch-4k-monitor-offers-glasses-free-3d?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T23:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lenovo's upcoming 27-inch 4K monitor offers a unique experience unlike any other display: glasses-free 3D that can be toggled on and off. According to Ars Technica, the monitor features a lenticular lens and real-time eye-tracking to create the effect. It's being targeted at content creators, like 3D graphic designers and developers. From the report: Like other glasses-less 3D screens, [Lenovo's ThinkVision 27 3D Monitor] works by projecting two different images to each of your eyes, resulting in a 3D effect where, as PR images would have you believe, it appears that the images are popping out of the screen. Lenovo says the monitor's 3D resolution is 1920x2160. The lenticular lens in the monitor is switchable, allowing for normal, 2D viewing at 3840x2160, too. The ThinkVision's 27-inch display gives workers a bigger palette. It also means the monitor can be a regular 2D monitor when needed. [...]
 
As a regular 2D monitor, the ThinkVision's specs are pretty standard. It's a 4K IPS screen claiming a 60 Hz refresh rate, 310 nits, a 1,000:1 contrast ratio, and 99 percent DCI-P3 and Adobe RGB color coverage with a Delta E under 2. Like a proper workplace monitor, there's also a strong port selection: two HDMI 2.1, one DisplayPort 1.4, four USB-A (3.1 Gen 1) ports, one USB-C port (3.2 Gen 1) with up to 15 W power delivery, RJ45, a 3.5mm jack, plus an upstream USB-C port with up to 100 W power delivery.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robinhood Bought Back Sam Bankman-Fried's Stake From US Government For $606 Million]]></title>
        <id>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/2227255/robinhood-bought-back-sam-bankman-frieds-stake-from-us-government-for-606-million?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/2227255/robinhood-bought-back-sam-bankman-frieds-stake-from-us-government-for-606-million?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T22:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Robinhood announced it has purchased more than 55 million shares of the firm previously held by former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried, which were seized in January by the U.S. Department of Justice as part of the criminal case against FTX and its executives. CoinTelegraph reports: The purchase had been expected. Robinhood's board of directors announced the approval of the deal in the company's Q4 2022 report, and an Aug. 30 SEC filing said the U.S. District Court for the Southern District of New York had approved the purchase "free and clear of any claims, interests, liens and encumbrances." Robinhood made the repurchase agreement with the U.S. Marshals Service. "We are happy to have completed the purchase of these shares and look forward to executing on our growth plans on behalf of our customers and shareholders," said Robinhood chief financial officer Jason Warnick.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hacker Gains Admin Control of Sourcegraph and Gives Free Access To the Masses]]></title>
        <id>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/2139242/hacker-gains-admin-control-of-sourcegraph-and-gives-free-access-to-the-masses?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/2139242/hacker-gains-admin-control-of-sourcegraph-and-gives-free-access-to-the-masses?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader quotes a report from Ars Technica: An unknown hacker gained administrative control of Sourcegraph, an AI-driven service used by developers at Uber, Reddit, Dropbox, and other companies, and used it to provide free access to resources that normally would have required payment. In the process, the hacker(s) may have accessed personal information belonging to Sourcegraph users, Diego Comas, Sourcegraph's head of security, said in a post on Wednesday. For paid users, the information exposed included license keys and the names and email addresses of license key holders. For non-paying users, it was limited to email addresses associated with their accounts. Private code, emails, passwords, usernames, or other personal information were inaccessible.
 
The hacker gained adminis…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Samsung Unveils Industry's First 32Gbit DDR5 Memory Die]]></title>
        <id>https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1955206/samsung-unveils-industrys-first-32gbit-ddr5-memory-die?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1955206/samsung-unveils-industrys-first-32gbit-ddr5-memory-die?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T21:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Samsung today revealed the world's first 32 Gb DDR5 DRAM die. From a report: The new memory die is made on the company's 12 nm-class DRAM fabrication process and not only offers increased density, but also lowers power consumption. The chip will allow Samsung to build record 1 TB RDIMMs for servers as well as lower costs of high-capacity memory modules. "With our 12nm-class 32 Gb DRAM, we have secured a solution that will enable DRAM modules of up to 1 TB, allowing us to be ideally positioned to serve the growing need for high-capacity DRAM in the era of AI (Artificial Intelligence) and big data," said SangJoon Hwang, executive vice president of DRAM product & technology at Samsung Electronics. 

32 Gb memory dies not only enable Samsung to build a regular, single-rank 32 GB module for client PCs using only eight single-die memory chips, but they also allow for higher capacity DIMMs that were not previously possible. We are talking about 1 TB memory modules using 40 8-Hi 3DS memory stacks based on eight 32 Gb memory devices. Such modules may sound overkill, but for artificial intelligence (AI), Big Data, and database servers, more DRAM capacity can easily be put to good use. Eventually, 1TB RDIMMs would allow for up to 12 TB of memory in a single socket server (e.g. AMD's EPYC 9004 platform), something that cannot be done now.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nvidia Quietly Cuts Price of Poorly Reviewed 16GB 4060 Ti Ahead of AMD Launch]]></title>
        <id>https://slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1937248/nvidia-quietly-cuts-price-of-poorly-reviewed-16gb-4060-ti-ahead-of-amd-launch?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1937248/nvidia-quietly-cuts-price-of-poorly-reviewed-16gb-4060-ti-ahead-of-amd-launch?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T20:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader shares a report: AMD last week announced what are probably the last major GPU launches of this generation of graphics cards: the $449 Radeon RX 7700 XT and $499 Radeon RX 7800 XT. AMD's pricing and performance numbers pit the cards against Nvidia's GeForce RTX 4060 Ti (specifically the $499 16GB version) and the $599 RTX 4070. AMD's pricing is aggressive enough that Nvidia is quietly cutting the prices of some 16GB RTX 4060 Ti cards to $449, to match the RX 7700 XT. 

The announcement about the $50 reduction was buried toward the bottom of an email that Nvidia sent to GPU reviewers ahead of AMD's launch next week; it also drew attention to Nvidia-specific features like DLSS upscaling and frame generation, which compete with AMD's GPU-agnostic FSR, plus recent DLSS improvements that improve ray-tracing performance.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[India Seeks To Top Its Moon Landing with Spacecraft To Study Sun]]></title>
        <id>https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1838208/india-seeks-to-top-its-moon-landing-with-spacecraft-to-study-sun?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1838208/india-seeks-to-top-its-moon-landing-with-spacecraft-to-study-sun?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hot on the heels of its lunar landing success, India is readying to blast a probe even deeper into space to study the sun. From a report: The country's first solar observation mission, named Aditya-L1, is set to be launched from India's main spaceport on Sriharikota, an island off the southern state of Andhra Pradesh, at 11:50 a.m. local time on Saturday. The spacecraft is scheduled to spend 125 days traveling 1.5 million kilometers (932,000 miles) to its destination, a point in space where objects stay put and consume less fuel. 

While arriving there would be an impressive achievement for ISRO, the Indian space agency, Aditya-L1 would have gone just a fraction of the 150 million km between Earth and the sun. For ISRO, success would be another major feat after India became the first country to land a spacecraft close to the lunar south pole in August. India has more ambitious projects in the works. A human spaceflight program aims to launch astronauts into orbit for the first time possibly by 2025, ISRO Chairman S Somanath said in an interview with news agency Asian News International. ISRO and NASA plan to cooperate on sending astronauts to the International Space Station and India is in discussions with Japan to work together on a mission.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Japan is Preparing For a Massive Earthquake]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1828253/japan-is-preparing-for-a-massive-earthquake?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1828253/japan-is-preparing-for-a-massive-earthquake?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T19:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The centenary of the Great Kanto earthquake brings angst, and lessons for the world. From a report: Every year on September 1st, Japan's ministers trek by foot to the prime minister's office to take part in a crisis simulation. Across the country, local officials and schoolchildren drill for disasters. The date marks the Great Kanto earthquake, a 7.9-magnitude tremor that struck near the capital back in 1923. The ensuing disaster killed at least 105,000 people, including around 70,000 in Tokyo itself, destroyed 370,000 homes and changed the course of Japanese history. 

This year's centenary of the disaster has occasioned much commemoration -- and angst. What will happen when the next Big One hits? Seismologists cannot predict earthquakes, but their statistical models, which are based on past patterns, can estimate the likelihood of one. The city government's experts reckon there is a 70% chance of a magnitude 7 or higher quake hitting the capital within the next 30 years. Far fewer people will probably die than during the disaster in 1923, thanks to better technology and planning: the worst case foresees some 6,000 deaths in the city. But millions of lives will be upended. 

Another, similarly likely scenario could be much worse. A Nankai Trough earthquake, envisaged south of Kansai, Japan's industrial heartland, could trigger a tsunami; as many as 323,000 might be killed, according to an official estimate. Japan's approach to the risks of such catastrophes offers insights for a warming world facing more frequent disasters. Quakes of this size could "challenge the survival of Japan as a state" and send economic shock waves around the globe, says Fukuwa Nobuo of Nagoya University. After the next Tokyo quake, recovering basic city functions could take weeks and rebuilding the capital could take years; direct damage alone could run to as much as $75bn. One piece of research estimates that gdp would dip by 11% following a Nankai earthquake.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spotify To Cut Back Promotional Spending on White Noise Podcasts]]></title>
        <id>https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1748216/spotify-to-cut-back-promotional-spending-on-white-noise-podcasts?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1748216/spotify-to-cut-back-promotional-spending-on-white-noise-podcasts?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T18:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spotify is cracking down on white-noise podcasters, reducing the advertising support for programmers that provide little more than soothing sounds like rain or chirping birds. From a report: In an email to creators Friday, the company highlighted changes to its Ambassador Ads program -- promotional spots for Spotify that podcasters read. The company pays hosts to read ads to encourage more creators to make shows and join the platform. As part of the change taking effect Oct. 1, white noise podcasters will no longer be eligible for such support, according to a person with knowledge of the matter. The company is also raising the audience threshold that conventional podcasters must meet to qualify for those ads to 1,000 unique Spotify listeners over the past 60 days from 100.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You can't fix core competency with a stern conversation]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/dhh/you-can-t-fix-core-competency-with-a-stern-conversation-b8a2f31f</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/you-can-t-fix-core-competency-with-a-stern-conversation-b8a2f31f"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T18:22:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When things aren't going well with a new hire, the problem usually falls into one of two categories: competency or engagement. If it's a problem with engagement – their style of collaboration, their communication, their approach – there's a good chance you can fix it with some clear feedback. But if the problem is with core competency – their technical skills – you can't expect to solve that with a stern conversation.
It's true that it might not be entirely clear in the early days of a new hire whether problems fall into one category or the other. But eventually it will be clear, and when it is, you have to act accordingly. 
Problems with engagement are often simply due to unstated assumptions. You expect someone to act a certain way, but they don't realize that, so they don't, and you're …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cybercrime To Cost Germany 206 Billion Euros in 2023, Survey Finds]]></title>
        <id>https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1733208/cybercrime-to-cost-germany-206-billion-euros-in-2023-survey-finds?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1733208/cybercrime-to-cost-germany-206-billion-euros-in-2023-survey-finds?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T18:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The theft of IT equipment and data, as well as digital and industrial espionage and sabotage, will cost Germany 206 billion euros ($224 billion) in 2023, German digital association Bitkom said on Friday. From a report: The damage will surpass the 200 billion euro mark for the third consecutive year, according to a Bitkom survey of more than 1,000 companies. "The German economy is a highly attractive target for criminals and hostile states. The boundaries between organised crime and state-controlled actors are blurred," Bitkom President Ralf Wintergerst said. Around three quarters of the companies surveyed suffered digital attacks in the past 12 months, falling from 84% of the companies in the previous year.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of Tough Mudder Racers Infected By Rugged, Nasty Bacterium]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/178227/hundreds-of-tough-mudder-racers-infected-by-rugged-nasty-bacterium?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/178227/hundreds-of-tough-mudder-racers-infected-by-rugged-nasty-bacterium?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T17:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of people who participated in a recent Tough Mudder event -- a very muddy obstacle course race -- held in Sonoma, California, have fallen ill with pustular rashes, lesions, fever, flu-like symptoms, nerve pain, and other symptoms, local health officials and media outlets report. From a report: The cases could be caused by various infectious agents, including Staphylococcus bacteria, but the leading culprit is the relatively obscure Aeromonas bacteria -- specifically A. hydrophila, according to the Sonoma County health department. In a statewide alert this week, the California Department of Public Health said it is considering it an Aeromonas outbreak, noting that multiple wound cultures have yielded the hardy bacterium. 

A spokesperson for the Sonoma County health department told the Los Angeles Times on Thursday that, based on calls and emails the department had received, health officials estimate that the outbreak involves around 300 cases. Tough Mudder participants, meanwhile, have tallied as many as 489 cases in online forums. The Tough Mudder event was held at the Sonoma Raceway on August 19 and 20, 2023, with symptoms of infection developing in cases within 12 to 48 hours afterward. The Sonoma County health department advisory noted that the race "involved extensive skin exposure to mud" and that participants with a rash, fever, or other symptoms should go to their health care provider or, if no provider is available, to a local emergency department.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dell and Samsung Grab First-Class Tickets For AI Hype Train]]></title>
        <id>https://slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1649252/dell-and-samsung-grab-first-class-tickets-for-ai-hype-train?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1649252/dell-and-samsung-grab-first-class-tickets-for-ai-hype-train?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T16:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dell and Samsung are the latest beneficiaries of the current frenzy of speculation surrounding anything AI related, with both vendors seeing a rise in share prices related to their future AI prospects. From a report: Shares in Dell were said to be up 8 percent in extended trading following the Round Rock company releasing its results for the second quarter of its financial year 2024. These showed that revenue was $22.9 billion, down 13 percent on the same period last year. However, this figure was also up 10 percent on the previous quarter, with the company attributing this growth to rising demand for AI-optimized servers, as well as its PowerStore and PowerFlex storage systems. AI accounted for 20 percent of server revenue in the first half of the year, Dell said. 

Similarly, Dell said it is seeing growth in demand for its workstations designed to help organizations run complex AI workloads locally, with its commercial client revenue hitting $10.6 billion. This accounted for the lion's share of the Client Solutions Group second quarter revenue of $12.9 billion, which was down 16 percent year-on-year but up 8 percent on the last quarter. Dell vice chairman and chief operating officer Jeff Clarke said that the company continued to focus on the most profitable segments of the market where he claimed Dell has a leading position.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paris Becomes the First European Capital To Ban Rented Electric Scooters]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1551253/paris-becomes-the-first-european-capital-to-ban-rented-electric-scooters?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1551253/paris-becomes-the-first-european-capital-to-ban-rented-electric-scooters?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader shares a report: Paris became the first European capital to outlaw the vehicles on Friday, following a vote in April in which Parisiens overwhelmingly supported a ban, although turnout was low. Privately owned e-scooters, which the city cannot regulate, are exempt. Since their eruption onto the streets and sidewalks of cities across the world in 2019, e-scooters have posed unique regulatory problems for city officials. The vehicles often stayed in legal limbo as officials mapped out charters for e-scooter operators, capped fleets and regulated parking. 

Cities like San Francisco and Miami temporarily banned e-scooters before reintroducing them. Santa Monica, Calif., successfully sued an e-scooter operator over its lack of licensing. And New York delayed the vehicles' arrival, citing security concerns. But no city has been as strict as Paris, where e-scooter users are mourning a cheap and flexible way of getting around without having to ride the crammed metro or use Velib', the popular but frequently overwhelmed bike-sharing system.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lidl Recalls Paw Patrol Snacks After Website on Packaging Displayed Porn]]></title>
        <id>https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1516252/lidl-recalls-paw-patrol-snacks-after-website-on-packaging-displayed-porn?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/09/01/1516252/lidl-recalls-paw-patrol-snacks-after-website-on-packaging-displayed-porn?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T15:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Supermarket giant Lidl has issued a recall of Paw Patrol snacks after the website listed on the products' packaging began displaying explicit content unsuitable for children. From a report: Lidl, which operates more than 12,000 stores globally, is urging shoppers in the United Kingdom to return the snacks for a full refund. Affected products include Paw Patrol Yummy Bakes and Paw Patrol Mini Biscotti, snacks recommended for children aged two and above. Lidl's recall notice dated August 22 warns that the product's packaging contains a web address that has been "compromised" to display content "not suitable for child consumption."







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Story: Configuring Identity: Adam Jacob and the Search for Self in Software]]></title>
        <id>38157a53-9b67-44db-8edb-24825c524f8b</id>
        <link href="https://corecursive.com/configuring-identity-adam-jacob/"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we go behind the scenes at Chef - the game changing infrastructure automation tool. Adam Jacob created Chef, and it became a massively popular DevOps tool. But despite Chef's success, Adam constantly battled self-doubt and finding his footing as a leader. 
 In this raw episode, Adam shares how the pressure of going from sysadmin to startup CEO caused an identity crisis. He opens up about the motivational speech that left him in tears, realizing his self-worth was too tied to Chef's outcomes. 
  
Episode Page
 Support The Show
 Subscribe To The Podcast
 Join The Newsletter]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CoRecursive: Coding Stories</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Experimenting With 3D Printing To Create Devices]]></title>
        <id>https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/2214247/apple-experimenting-with-3d-printing-to-create-devices?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/2214247/apple-experimenting-with-3d-printing-to-create-devices?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T00:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[According to Bloombeg's Mark Gurman (paywalled), Apple is experimenting with a new 3D-printing manufacturing process for some device production, starting with the upcoming Apple Watch Series 9 models. MacRumors reports: The new manufacturing process that Apple is testing would use less material than the large slabs of metal that are needed for traditional CNC manufacturing, plus it would cut down on the time that it takes to make new devices. With a technique called "binder jetting," Apple is able to print a device's outline at close to its actual shape using a powdered substance. A second process uses heat and pressure to squeeze the material into a substance that feels like steel, and it is then refined with milling.
 
Gurman's information echoes what we've already heard from Apple analyst Ming-Chi Kuo. Back in July, Kuo said that the upcoming second-generation Apple Watch Ultra will include 3D printed mechanical parts. Specifically, he claimed that Apple is "actively adopting 3D printing technology," and that some of the titanium components in the new Apple Watch Ultra would be 3D printed. Gurman claims that Apple plans to use this new 3D printing method for the chassis of the stainless steel Apple Watch Series 9 models rather than components for the Ultra but either way, it sounds like Apple is more actively testing this manufacturing method as of 2023. Gurman says that Apple plans to 3D print titanium devices in 2024. The report notes that the shift to 3D printing would also "allow Apple to improve manufacturing times and potentially cut down on costs."







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magic Leap AR Headset Will 'Cease To Function' In 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/2317216/magic-leap-ar-headset-will-cease-to-function-in-2025?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/2317216/magic-leap-ar-headset-will-cease-to-function-in-2025?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T00:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader quotes a report from UploadVR: Magic Leap 1 AR headsets will 'cease to function' from December 31, 2024, the company announced. Magic Leap 1 launched in mid 2018 as the first transparent AR headset marketed and sold to consumers. The headset is powered by a tethered waist-mounted compute pack and came with a single tracked controller, though it got hand tracking support too. Content for the device included avatar chat, a floating web browser, a Wayfair app for seeing how furniture might look in your room, two games made by Insomniac Games, and a Spotify background app.
 
But Magic Leap 1's eye-watering $2300 price and the limitations of transparent optics (even today) meant it reportedly fell significantly short of sales expectations. Transparent AR currently provides a much smaller field of view than the opaque display systems of VR-style headsets, despite costing significantly more. And Magic Leap 1's form factor wasn't suitable for outdoor use, so it didn't provide the out-of-home functionality AR glasses promise to one day like on-foot navigation, translation, and contextual information. The Information reported that Magic Leap's founder, the CEO at the time, originally expected it to sell over one million units in the first year. In reality it reportedly sold just 6000 units in the first six months.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[crates.io Postmortem: User Uploaded Malware]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/09/01/crates-io-malware-postmortem.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/09/01/crates-io-malware-postmortem.html"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Summary
On August 16, the crates.io team was notified by Louis Lang at Phylum of a new user who had uploaded nine crates that typosquatted1 popular crates with ill intent. The crates were immediately yanked and the user account locked, and the crates were then fully removed from the crates.io file store on August 18.
Phylum have also written their own blog on this incident.
Contents
These crates contained malicious build.rs files that would attempt to send metadata from the user's computer to a Telegram2 channel, including their operating system, IP address, and geolocation information based on their IP address.3
One version of one crate also contained a copy of the PuTTY4 installer, with the build.rs spawning PuTTY instead of sending metadata to Telegram. Our assumption is that this was a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Inside Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI Quadcopter 'Swift' Beats Top Human Drone Racers]]></title>
        <id>https://slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/2154254/ai-quadcopter-swift-beats-top-human-drone-racers?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/2154254/ai-quadcopter-swift-beats-top-human-drone-racers?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T23:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An autonomous, artificial-intelligence-powered drone called Swift has beaten humanity's best drone racers. "The AI-equipped drone, developed by researchers at the University of Zurich, came out on top in 15 out of 25 races and recorded the single fastest lap time," reports Gizmodo. The findings have been published in the journal Nature. From the report: Swift beat the humans in the niche but growing sport of first-person view drone racing. Human competitors navigate using a headset connected to a camera on their drones to pilot a quadcopter through complex obstacle courses at extreme speeds, with the goal of finishing the race with the fastest time and avoiding taking too much damage in the process. Drones in these races can top 50 miles per hour when they're really buzzing. The [video her…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wireless Carriers Are Messing With Your Autopay Discount]]></title>
        <id>https://mobile.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/2146250/wireless-carriers-are-messing-with-your-autopay-discount?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://mobile.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/2146250/wireless-carriers-are-messing-with-your-autopay-discount?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T22:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[According to a new report by The Wall Street Journal, mobile carriers including Verizon, AT&T and T-Mobile are all requiring customers to switch to a debit card or bank account withdrawal in order to receive an autopay discount on their plan. Verizon has included this requirement for years, but in the past few months the other two carriers have quietly added it too. The Verge reports: The new rule goes into effect for AT&T customers on October 2nd, and as a gesture of goodwill, the company will only reduce your discount if you continue to pay with a credit card. Those who register for autopay with a bank or debit card will receive $10 off; a credit card will only get you $5. T-Mobile's change went into effect in July, also eliminating Apple Pay and Google Pay as methods eligible for the $5 discount. Oh, and technically, you can qualify for Verizon's autopay discount with a credit card -- it just has to be a Verizon Visa card.
 
AT&T and T-Mobile aren't just making this a requirement for new customers -- the change is being applied to all postpaid accounts. Even if you've been receiving the discount for years with a credit card, you'll have to make the switch in order to keep your discount. And it adds up -- the discounts are applied for each line on your plan, so if your whole family is on the same plan, it's a significant amount of money.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Texas Law Requiring Age Verification On Porn Sites Ruled Unconstitutional]]></title>
        <id>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/2114232/texas-law-requiring-age-verification-on-porn-sites-ruled-unconstitutional?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/2114232/texas-law-requiring-age-verification-on-porn-sites-ruled-unconstitutional?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader quotes a report from Ars Technica: The day before a Texas antiporn law that requires age verification to access adult websites was set to take effect, the state's attorney general, Angela Colmenero, has been at least temporarily blocked from enforcing the law. US District Judge David Alan Ezra granted a preliminary injunction temporarily blocking enforcement after the Free Speech Coalition (FSC) joined adult performers and sites like Pornhub in a lawsuit opposing the law. Today, they convinced Ezra that Texas' law violates the First Amendment and would have "a chilling effect on legally-protected speech," FSC said in a press release.
 
"This is a huge and important victory against the rising tide of censorship online," Alison Boden, FSC's executive director, said. "From…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK Government Seeks Expanded Use of AI-based Facial Recognition By Police]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1818201/uk-government-seeks-expanded-use-of-ai-based-facial-recognition-by-police?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1818201/uk-government-seeks-expanded-use-of-ai-based-facial-recognition-by-police?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T21:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK's Home Office is looking to increase its use of controversial facial recognition technologies to track and find criminals within policing and other security agencies. From a report: In a document released on Wednesday, the government outlined its ambitions to potentially deploy new biometric systems nationally over the next 12 to 18 months. The move comes after privacy campaigners and independent academics criticised the technology for being inaccurate and biased, particularly against darker-skinned people. 

MPs have previously called for a moratorium on its use on the general population until clear laws are established by parliament. The government is calling for submissions from companies for technologies that "can resolve identity using facial features and landmarks," including for live facial recognition which involves screening the general public for specific individuals on police watch lists. 

In particular, the Home Office is highlighting its interest in novel artificial intelligence technologies that could process facial data efficiently to identify individuals, and software that could be integrated with existing technologies deployed by the department and with CCTV cameras. Facial recognition software has been used by South Wales Police and London's Metropolitan Police over the past five years across multiple trials in public spaces including shopping centres, during events such as the Notting Hill Carnival and, more recently, during the coronation.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Removes 'Pirate' URLs From Users' Privately Saved Links]]></title>
        <id>https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/187220/google-removes-pirate-urls-from-users-privately-saved-links?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/187220/google-removes-pirate-urls-from-users-privately-saved-links?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T20:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To date, Google has processed more than seven billion copyright takedown requests for its search engine. The majority of the reported links are purged from Google's search index, as required by the DMCA. Recently, however, Google appears to gone a step further, using search takedowns to "moderate" users' privately saved links collections. TorrentFreak: A few hours ago, Eddie Roosenmaallen shared an email from Google, notifying him that a link had been removed from his Google Saved collection because it violates Google's policy. The reason cited for the removal is the "downstream impact," as the URL in question is "blocked by Google Search." 

"The following saved item in one of your collections was determined to violate Google's policy. As a result, the item will be moderated..," Google writes, pointing out a defunct KickassTorrents domain as the problem. Initially, it was suggested that this removal impacted Google's synched Chrome bookmarks but further research reveals that's not the case. Instead, the removals apply to Google's saved feature. This Google service allows users to save and organize links, similar to what Pinterest does. These link collections can be private or shared with third parties.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US Copyright Office Wants To Hear What People Think About AI and Copyright]]></title>
        <id>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1758212/us-copyright-office-wants-to-hear-what-people-think-about-ai-and-copyright?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1758212/us-copyright-office-wants-to-hear-what-people-think-about-ai-and-copyright?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T20:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The US Copyright Office is opening a public comment period around AI and copyright issues beginning August 30th as the agency figures out how to approach the subject. From a report: As announced [PDF] in the Federal Register, the agency wants to answer three main questions: how AI models should use copyrighted data in training; whether AI-generated material can be copyrighted even without a human involved; and how copyright liability would work with AI. It also wants comments around AI possibly violating publicity rights but noted these are not technically copyright issues. The Copyright Office said if AI does mimic voices, likenesses, or art styles, it may impact state-mandated rules around publicity and unfair competition laws. Written comments are due on October 18th, and replies must be submitted to the Copyright Office by November 15th. 

The copyright status of AI training data and the output of generative AI tools has become a hot topic for politicians, artists, authors, and even civil rights groups, making it a potential testing ground for coming AI regulation. The Copyright Office says that "over the past several years, the Office has begun to receive applications to register works containing AI-generated material." It may use the comments to inform how it decides to grant copyright in the future. The Copyright Office was involved in a lawsuit last year after it refused to grant Stephen Thaler rights to an image created by an AI platform. Earlier this month, a Washington, DC, court sided with the US Copyright Office in the case, stating copyright has never been handed to any work without a human involved.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starfield's 1,000 Planets May Be One Giant Leap for Game Design]]></title>
        <id>https://games.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1752251/starfields-1000-planets-may-be-one-giant-leap-for-game-design?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://games.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1752251/starfields-1000-planets-may-be-one-giant-leap-for-game-design?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T19:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The stakes are high for Bethesda's newest role-playing game. Microsoft needs an Xbox hit, and players are hungry for an expansive and satisfying space adventure. From a report: Starfield almost immediately nudges its players to the edges of the cosmos. In the opening hours of the role-playing video game, it's possible to land your spaceship on Earth's moon or zip 16 light-years to Alpha Centauri. When you open your map and zoom out from a planet, you can behold its surrounding solar system; zoom out again, and you're scrolling past luminous stars and the mysterious worlds that orbit them. That sprawling celestial journey within Starfield, developed by Bethesda Game Studios, reveals both the tremendous potential and the monumental challenge of an open-world space adventure. Bethesda has hyped an expansive single-player campaign with 1,000 explorable planets. And expectations around the game, officially releasing on Sept. 6 after a 10-month delay, are nearly as vast. 

It's the first new universe in 25 years for Bethesda, known for the Elder Scrolls and Fallout series. It's also a high-stakes moment for Microsoft, which makes the Xbox and has long faced criticism that it produces fewer hit games than its console rivals, Sony and Nintendo. To compete, Microsoft went on a spending spree, acquiring Bethesda's parent company in 2020 and agreeing to purchase Activision Blizzard in 2022, a $69 billion bet that is being challenged by regulators. Now Bethesda must deliver. Known for letting players navigate competing factions and undertake eccentric quests, the studio hopes Starfield will dazzle those clamoring for engaging encounters with alien life-forms or space mercenaries as well as a sense of boundless exploration.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[With Version 117, Firefox Finally Speaks Chrome's Translation Language]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1658259/with-version-117-firefox-finally-speaks-chromes-translation-language?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1658259/with-version-117-firefox-finally-speaks-chromes-translation-language?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T18:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest version of the flagship FOSS browser is out, and it's picked up one of the main features for which we keep Chrome around. From a report: The Firefox version 117 feature list might not look all that impressive, but it does have a big-ticket feature that may tempt people back: automatic translation. The snag is it's disabled by default in the release version, and you'll have to manually enable it. Although it was enabled in the betas, Mozilla has decided to go for a staged rollout and not enable it for everyone until Firefox 118 in six weeks or so. 

The new feature is integrated, privacy-respecting machine translation between multiple languages. This was already possible in older versions, but it needed an extension, and that had two side effects. One is that the extension hooked deep into the core of the browser in ways that Mozilla wasn't comfortable about, and the other is that once your text had been sent out to a third-party website, it could be snooped upon -- but the victims of any snooping would blame the browser, even if it wasn't the browser's fault. To enable it, go to the configuration page (enter about:config in the address bar), and search for a setting called browser.translations.enable.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Removes Fake Signal and Telegram Apps Hosted on Play]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1655233/google-removes-fake-signal-and-telegram-apps-hosted-on-play?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1655233/google-removes-fake-signal-and-telegram-apps-hosted-on-play?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T18:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers say they have found fake apps in Google Play that masqueraded as legitimate ones for the Signal and Telegram messaging platforms. The malicious apps could pull messages or other sensitive information from legitimate accounts when users took certain actions. ArsTechnica: An app with the name Signal Plus Messenger was available on Play for nine months and had been downloaded from Play roughly 100 times before Google took it down last April after being tipped off by security firm ESET. It was also available in the Samsung app store and on signalplus[.]org, a dedicated website mimicking the official Signal.org. An app calling itself FlyGram, meanwhile, was created by the same threat actor and was available through the same three channels. Google removed it from Play in 2021. Both apps remain available in the Samsung store. 

Both apps were built on open source code available from Signal and Telegram. Interwoven into that code was an espionage tool tracked as BadBazaar. The Trojan has been linked to a China-aligned hacking group tracked as GREF. BadBazaar has been used previously to target Uyghurs and other Turkic ethnic minorities. The FlyGram malware was also shared in a Uyghur Telegram group, further aligning it to previous targeting by the BadBazaar malware family. Signal Plus could monitor sent and received messages and contacts if people connected their infected device to their legitimate Signal number, as is normal when someone first installs Signal on their device. Doing so caused the malicious app to send a host of private information to the attacker, including the device IMEI number, phone number, MAC address, operator details, location data, Wi-Fi information, emails for Google accounts, contact list, and a PIN used to transfer texts in the event one was set up by the user.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scientologists Ask Federal Government To Restrict Right To Repair]]></title>
        <id>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1647203/scientologists-ask-federal-government-to-restrict-right-to-repair?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1647203/scientologists-ask-federal-government-to-restrict-right-to-repair?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T17:23:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The organization that represents the literary works of Scientology founder L. Ron Hubbard has filed a petition with the Federal Government, asking it to make it illegal to circumvent software locks for the repair of a highly specific set of electronic devices, according to a letter reviewed by 404 Media. From the report: The letter doesn't refer to any single device, but experts say the petition covers Scientology's "E-Meter," a "religious artifact" and electronic that is core to Scientology. Author Services Inc., a group "representing the literary, theatrical, and musical works of L. Ron Hubbard," told the U.S. Copyright Office that it opposes the renewal of an exemption to Section 1201 of the Digital Millennium Copyright Act that makes it legal for consumers to hack their personal electronics for the purposes of repair. 

This exemption to copyright law is needed because many electronics manufacturers put arbitrary software locks, Digital Rights Management systems, or other technological prevention measures that stop consumers from diagnosing or repairing devices unless they are authorized to do so. Special exemptions to copyright law make it legal for farmers to hack past John Deere's DRM to fix their tractors, consumers to use software tools to help them repair certain parts of game consoles, or use third-party software to circumvent repair locks on printers, air conditioners, laptops, etc.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dutch E-Bike Brand VanMoof Bought Out of Bankruptcy by Scooter Maker]]></title>
        <id>https://slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1621218/dutch-e-bike-brand-vanmoof-bought-out-of-bankruptcy-by-scooter-maker?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1621218/dutch-e-bike-brand-vanmoof-bought-out-of-bankruptcy-by-scooter-maker?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T16:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[VanMoof, the Dutch e-bike maker that gained a zealous following but declared bankruptcy last month, has been acquired by Lavoie, an upscale electric scooter company, the firms announced on Thursday. From a report: Riders of the expensive and technologically advanced VanMoof bikes were left in limbo by the company's bankruptcy, because the machines are built from proprietary parts that only the company made and many of the bikes' functions are linked to a smartphone app that runs on the company's servers. Despite the buzz around the brand, VanMoof had run into financial problems that led to a production backlog and monthslong waits for sales and repairs. 

But riders will not be completely out of limbo under the new ownership. "What they can't expect in the first couple of weeks is definitive answers to the problems," said Nick Fry, the chairman of McLaren Applied, the British motorsports technology company that owns Lavoie. The price of the acquisition was not disclosed, but Mr. Fry said Lavoie would spend "tens of millions" on the transaction as well as in investments over the coming months to "rectify some of the challenges we face." He said, "this is not going to be a walk in the park. This is going to be a challenge." One of the new owner's priorities, he added, was improving the availability of parts and repairs, something that had become increasingly difficult for VanMoof owners. Regular bike shops could not -- or sometimes would not -- fix the bikes.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US Says It Has Not Blocked Chip Sales To Middle East]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/167230/us-says-it-has-not-blocked-chip-sales-to-middle-east?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/167230/us-says-it-has-not-blocked-chip-sales-to-middle-east?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T16:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A U.S. Department of Commerce spokesperson on Thursday said the Biden administration "has not blocked chip sales to the Middle East." From a report: The comments come after artificial intelligence chip firms Nvidia and Advanced Micro Devices received notifications from U.S. officials about new export licensing requirements to ship chips to some countries in the Middle East.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Tropical Island With the Hot Domain Name]]></title>
        <id>https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1537207/the-tropical-island-with-the-hot-domain-name?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/08/31/1537207/the-tropical-island-with-the-hot-domain-name?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T15:36:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A tiny island in the Caribbean is now sitting on a digital treasure. From a report: Anguilla, a tropical British territory, is known for its coral reefs and white sand beaches. Since the 1990s, however, it's also been in charge of assigning internet addresses that end in .ai to residents and businesses looking to register websites. It was one of hundreds of country-specific domain names and easy to overlook -- until recently. Stability.ai, Elon Musk's X.ai and Character.ai are just a few of the hot artificial intelligence startups that have snapped up the .ai domain assigned to the islands and cays that comprise Anguilla. Plenty of tech giants have their own web addresses ending in .ai as well: Google.ai and Facebook.ai route visitors to their company's AI-focused webpages and Microsoft.ai shows off the company's Azure AI services. 

The total number of registrations of sites ending with these two letters has effectively doubled in the past year to 287,432, according to Vince Cate, who for decades has managed the .ai domain for Anguilla. Cate estimates Anguilla will bring in as much as $30 million in domain-registration fees for 2023. Once one of the many obscure top-level domains assigned to countries and territories, .ai websites experienced a slow but steady increase in demand in recent years. But the sudden spike in .ai domains nine months ago highlights the broader frenzy around artificial intelligence and its ripple effects throughout the global economy. Since ChatGPT launched, a growing number of tech companies have raced to raise billions in capital, scoop up engineering talent and secure powerful but increasingly scarce chips. A domain may sound less essential, but for an industry obsessed with clever branding, the right name can be everything. "Since November 30, things are very different here," Cate said, referring to the date when ChatGPT launched publicly.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minding the small stuff in pull request reviews]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/jorge/minding-the-small-stuff-in-pull-request-reviews-b923720d</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/jorge/minding-the-small-stuff-in-pull-request-reviews-b923720d"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T07:18:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article was originally published in the 37signals dev blog.

Nitpicking in pull requests reviews means offering insight that looks excessive, pedantic, and unimportant. It’s a pejorative term. I don’t question there are cases where the term applies, but many folks assimilate it to paying attention to the small stuff. By projecting all these negative connotations, this practice suddenly becomes undesirable: mind the big picture or leave the pull request alone. With that, we disagree. Small stuff when writing code matters, a lot.


Names matter
Naming things is a usual suspect when illustrating nitpicking. It’s also the example I have the hardest time swallowing. With the importance of names to make code understandable, how can anyone consider discussing those superfluous?

Check what J…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jorge Manrubia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call of Duty Will Use AI To Moderate Voice Chats]]></title>
        <id>https://games.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/2122229/call-of-duty-will-use-ai-to-moderate-voice-chats?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://games.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/2122229/call-of-duty-will-use-ai-to-moderate-voice-chats?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T00:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activision has partnered with a company called Modulate to moderate voice chats using an AI technology called ToxMod. According to The Verge, the tool "will work to identify behaviors like hate speech, discrimination, and harassment in real time." From the report: ToxMod's initial beta rollout in North America begins today. It's active within Call of Duty: Modern Warfare II and Call of Duty: Warzone. A "full worldwide release" (it does not include Asia, the press release notes) will follow on November 10th with the release of Call of Duty: Modern Warfare III, this year's new entry in the franchise. Modulate's press release doesn't include too many details about how exactly ToxMod works. Its website notes that the tool "triages voice chat to flag bad behavior, analyzes the nuances of each conversation to determine toxicity, and enables moderators to quickly respond to each incident by supplying relevant and accurate context."
 
The company's CEO said in a recent interview that the tool aims to go beyond mere transcription; it takes factors like a player's emotions and volume into context as well in order to differentiate harmful statements from playful ones. It is noteworthy that the tool (for now, at least) will not actually take action against players based on its data but will merely submit reports to Activision's moderators.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saudi Man Receives Death Penalty For Posts Online]]></title>
        <id>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/2117226/saudi-man-receives-death-penalty-for-posts-online?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/2117226/saudi-man-receives-death-penalty-for-posts-online?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T00:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader quotes a report from the Associated Press: A Saudi court has sentenced a man to death over his posts on X, formerly known as Twitter, and his activity on YouTube, the latest in a widening crackdown on dissent in the kingdom that has drawn international criticism. The judgement against Mohammed bin Nasser al-Ghamdi, seen Wednesday by The Associated Press, comes against the backdrop of doctoral student Salma al-Shehab and others facing decades-long prison sentences over their comments online. The sentences appear part of Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman's wider effort to stamp out any defiance in the kingdom as he pursues massive building projects and other diplomatic deals to raise his profile globally.
 
According to court documents, the charges levied against al-Ghamdi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Is Discontinuing Visual Studio For Mac After Major Overhaul]]></title>
        <id>https://apple.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/2057208/microsoft-is-discontinuing-visual-studio-for-mac-after-major-overhaul?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://apple.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/2057208/microsoft-is-discontinuing-visual-studio-for-mac-after-major-overhaul?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T23:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft is discontinuing Visual Studio for Mac, committing to security updates and platform update compatibility for the next 12 months. 9to5Mac reports: "With today's announcement, we're redirecting our resources and focus to enhance Visual Studio and VS Code, optimizing them for cross-platform development," the company said in the announcement.
"No new framework, runtime, or language support will be added to Visual Studio for Mac." The company added: "We will also continue to provide runtime and workload updates so you can continue building and shipping applications built on .NET 6, .NET 7, and the Mono frameworks. While not officially supported, we've also enabled rudimentary support for .NET 8 in Visual Studio for Mac for building and debugging applications."
 
Once the wheels fall off Visual Studio for Mac, Microsoft recommends accessing its IDE through Windows in a machine virtual on the Mac or in the cloud. Otherwise, Microsoft points to cross-platform compatible developer technology that will run on macOS: "The recently announced C# Dev Kit, .NET MAUI, and Unity Extensions for VS Code are available in preview and are intended to augment VS Code's capabilities for .NET and C# developers. These extensions operate natively across all supported platforms, including macOS, and the experience using these will continue to be improved as they move from preview to GA and beyond."







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MTA Website 'Feature' Lets You Track Subway Riders' Locations]]></title>
        <id>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/2043215/mta-website-feature-lets-you-track-subway-riders-locations?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/2043215/mta-website-feature-lets-you-track-subway-riders-locations?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T22:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Slash_Account_Dot shares a report from 404 Media, written by cybersecurity journalist Joseph Cox: In the mid-afternoon one Saturday earlier this month, the target got on the New York subway. I knew what station they entered the subway at and at what specific time. They then entered another station a few hours later. If I had kept monitoring this person, I would have figured out the subway station they often start a journey at, which is near where they live. I would also know what specific time this person may go to the subway each day. During all this monitoring, I wasn't anywhere near the rider. I didn't even need to see them with my own eyes. Instead, I was sitting inside an apartment, following their movements through a feature on a Metropolitan Transportation Authority (MTA) website, w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EPA Removes Federal Protections For Most of the Country's Wetlands]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/2049255/epa-removes-federal-protections-for-most-of-the-countrys-wetlands?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/2049255/epa-removes-federal-protections-for-most-of-the-countrys-wetlands?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader quotes a report from NPR: The Environmental Protection Agency removed federal protections for a majority of the country's wetlands on Tuesday to comply with a recent U.S. Supreme Court ruling. The EPA and Department of the Army announced a final rule amending the definition of protected "waters of the United States" in light of the decision in Sackett v. EPA in May, which narrowed the scope of the Clean Water Act and the agency's power to regulate waterways and wetlands. A 2006 Supreme Court decision determined that wetlands would be protected if they had a "significant nexus" to major waterways. This year's court decision undid that standard. The EPA's new rule "removes the significant nexus test from consideration when identifying tributaries and other waters as federally protected," the agency said.
 
In May, Justice Samuel Alito said the navigable U.S. waters regulated by the EPA under the Clean Water Act do not include many previously regulated wetlands. Writing the court's decision, he said the law includes only streams, oceans, rivers and lakes, and wetlands with a "continuous surface connection to those bodies." The EPA said the rule will take effect immediately. "The agencies are issuing this amendment to the 2023 rule expeditiously -- three months after the Supreme Court decision -- to provide clarity and a path forward consistent with the ruling," the agency said. As a result of the rule change, protections for many waterways and wetlands will now fall to states.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FCC Says 'Too Bad' To ISPs Complaining That Listing Every Fee is Too Hard]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1847258/fcc-says-too-bad-to-isps-complaining-that-listing-every-fee-is-too-hard?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1847258/fcc-says-too-bad-to-isps-complaining-that-listing-every-fee-is-too-hard?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T21:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Federal Communications Commission yesterday rejected requests to eliminate an upcoming requirement that Internet service providers list all of their monthly fees. From a report: Five major trade groups representing US broadband providers petitioned the FCC in January to scrap the requirement before it takes effect. In June, Comcast told the FCC that the listing-every-fee rule "impose[s] significant administrative burdens and unnecessary complexity in complying with the broadband label requirements." The five trade groups kept up the pressure earlier this month in a meeting with FCC officials and in a filing that complained that listing every fee is too hard. The FCC refused to bend, announcing yesterday that the rules will take effect without any major changes. 

"Every consumer needs transparent information when making decisions about what Internet service offering makes the most sense for their family or household. No one wants to be hit with charges they didn't ask for or they did not expect," FCC Chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel said. Yesterday's order "largely affirms the rules... while making some revisions and clarifications such as modifying provider record-keeping requirements when directing consumers to a label on an alternative sales channel and confirming that providers may state 'taxes included' when their price already incorporates taxes," the FCC said.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of Thousands Trafficked To Work as Online Scammers in Southeast Asia, Says UN Report]]></title>
        <id>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1840248/hundreds-of-thousands-trafficked-to-work-as-online-scammers-in-southeast-asia-says-un-report?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1840248/hundreds-of-thousands-trafficked-to-work-as-online-scammers-in-southeast-asia-says-un-report?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T20:41:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of thousands of people are being forcibly engaged by organised criminal gangs into online criminality in Southeast Asia - from romance-investment scams and crypto fraud to illegal gambling - a report issued today by the UN Human Rights Office shows. From a report: Victims face a range of serious violations and abuses, including threats to their safety and security; and many have been subjected to torture and cruel, inhuman and degrading treatment or punishment, arbitrary detention, sexual violence, forced labour, and other human rights abuses, the report says. "People who are coerced into working in these scamming operations endure inhumane treatment while being forced to carry out crimes. They are victims. They are not criminals," said UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Turk. 

"In continuing to call for justice for those who have been defrauded through online criminality, we must not forget that this complex phenomenon has two sets of victims." The enormity of online scam trafficking in Southeast Asia is difficult to estimate, the reports says, because of the clandestine nature and gaps in the official response. Credible sources indicate that at least 120,000 people across Myanmar may be held in situations where they are forced to carry out online scams, with estimates in Cambodia similarly at around 100,000. Other States in the region, including Lao PDR, the Philippines and Thailand, have also been identified as main countries of destination or transit where at least tens of thousands of people have been involved. The scam centres generate revenue amounting to billions of US dollars each year.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenAI Disputes Authors' Claims That Every ChatGPT Response is Derivative Work]]></title>
        <id>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1737241/openai-disputes-authors-claims-that-every-chatgpt-response-is-derivative-work?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1737241/openai-disputes-authors-claims-that-every-chatgpt-response-is-derivative-work?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenAI has responded to a pair of nearly identical class-action lawsuits from book authors -- including Sarah Silverman, Paul Tremblay, Mona Awad, Chris Golden, and Richard Kadrey -- who earlier this summer alleged that ChatGPT was illegally trained on pirated copies of their books. From a report: In OpenAI's motion to dismiss (filed in both lawsuits), the company asked a US district court in California to toss all but one claim alleging direct copyright infringement, which OpenAI hopes to defeat at "a later stage of the case." The authors' other claims -- alleging vicarious copyright infringement, violation of the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA), unfair competition, negligence, and unjust enrichment -- need to be "trimmed" from the lawsuits "so that these cases do not proceed to d…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaked Microsoft Memo Tells Managers Not To Use Budget Cuts as Explainer for Lack of Pay Rises]]></title>
        <id>https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1727202/leaked-microsoft-memo-tells-managers-not-to-use-budget-cuts-as-explainer-for-lack-of-pay-rises?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1727202/leaked-microsoft-memo-tells-managers-not-to-use-budget-cuts-as-explainer-for-lack-of-pay-rises?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T19:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader shares a report: Microsoft employees were already expecting lackluster pay rises. In a company-wide email sent earlier this year, the tech company's CEO Satya Nadella warned staff of salary freezes and cuts to the bonusbudget. But despite previous transparency around the cost-cutting measures, employees enquiring about how the budget cuts have impacted their performance review will now be fobbed off. According to leaked guidance, managers are being ordered to dodge such questions in the name of company culture. "It's natural for employees to ask questions about budget given the decisions shared in Satya's email," the guidance reportedly states. "However, it's most important to focus discussions with direct reports on their impact for the past fiscal year and directly tie it to their rewards." 

Managers should not use the budget cuts as an "explanation" for compensation decisions for individual employees and instead should emphasize that the employee's own "impact" determines "rewards." "Using budgets or factors besides the employee's impact as an explanation for an employee's rewards will erode trust and confidence within your team," the guide cautions. "Reinforce that every year offers unique opportunity for impact, and we increase our high expectations, regardless of our budget."







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UN Backs New Term For Conservation Talks]]></title>
        <id>https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1719203/un-backs-new-term-for-conservation-talks?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1719203/un-backs-new-term-for-conservation-talks?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T18:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The word "funga" should be used alongside flora and fauna when discussing conservation issues to reflect the importance of fungi to ecosystem health, a UN body has said. From a report: The secretariat of the UN convention on biological diversity (UNCBD) said it was time that fungi were "recognised and protected on an equal footing with animals and plants in legal conservation frameworks." 

"Whenever referring to the macroscopic diversity of life on Earth, we should use 'flora, fauna and funga,' and 'animal, plants and fungi,'" it said in an Instagram post. Mycologists, mostly from Latin America, established the term "funga" five years ago. It refers to the levels of diversity of fungi in any given place, and is analogous to "flora and fauna," which refer to plants and animals. Unlike flora and fauna, it is not a Latin term but was chosen because it is morphologically similar. "Just like mycelium, mycologically inclusive language will spread unseen but profound [sic], permeating public consciousness (and policy) to acknowledge fungi's vital role in the grand web of life on and in Earth," it said.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU Fossil Fuel Burning for Electricity Fell To Lowest on Record in 2023, Data Shows]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1713244/eu-fossil-fuel-burning-for-electricity-fell-to-lowest-on-record-in-2023-data-shows?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1713244/eu-fossil-fuel-burning-for-electricity-fell-to-lowest-on-record-in-2023-data-shows?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T18:03:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The European Union is stoking its power plants with fewer lumps of coal and barrels of oil and gas than it has ever recorded, data shows. From a report: The 27 member states burned 17% less fossil fuel to make electricity between January and June 2023 than over the same period the year before, a study from the clean energy thinktank Ember found. The EU made 410TWh of electricity from sources that release planet-heating gases, which analysts say is the lowest level since 2015 -- the first year for which they have monthly data -- and "very likely" since 2000. 

The drop in fossil fuel generation was driven by a fall in demand for electricity, as well as some growth in clean power, the study found. "We're glad to see fossil fuels down, but in the long-term it is not going to be sustainable to rely on the fall in demand to do this," said Matt Ewen, a data analyst at Ember and author of the report. "We have to be replacing this energy rather than just expecting it to go away and not be used." To try to stop the planet heating, the EU has promised to cut greenhouse gas pollution by at least 55% from 1990 levels by the end of the decade, and hit net zero emissions by 2050. To get there, it will probably have to use less energy but more electricity than it does today, as more people heat homes and drive cars with electricity instead of fossil fuels.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon CEO Says 'It's Probably Not Going To Work Out' For Employees Who Defy Return-to-Office Policy]]></title>
        <id>https://slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/178208/amazon-ceo-says-its-probably-not-going-to-work-out-for-employees-who-defy-return-to-office-policy?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/178208/amazon-ceo-says-its-probably-not-going-to-work-out-for-employees-who-defy-return-to-office-policy?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T17:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon employees have been pushing back against the company's return-to-office policy for months -- and it seems CEO Andy Jassy has had enough. From a report: During a pre-recorded internal Q&A session earlier this month, Jassy told employees it was "past the time to disagree and commit" with the policy, which requires corporate employees to be in the office three days a week. The phrase "disagree and commit" is one of Amazon's leadership principles, and was used often by the company's founder and current executive chairman, Jeff Bezos. "If you can't disagree and commit, it's probably not going to work out for you at Amazon," Jassy said, adding it wasn't right for some employees to be in the office three days a week while others refuse to do so.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sony Jacking Up Annual PlayStation Plus Plans By as Much as $40]]></title>
        <id>https://games.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1650242/sony-jacking-up-annual-playstation-plus-plans-by-as-much-as-40?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://games.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1650242/sony-jacking-up-annual-playstation-plus-plans-by-as-much-as-40?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T16:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A couple months after Microsoft revealed plans to increase Game Pass subscription prices, Sony is getting in on the act. From a report: The company is bumping up the annual prices of all three PlayStation Plus plans on September 6th. An annual Essential subscription will soon cost $80 per year, up from $60. The Extra plan is going up by $35 to $135 per year, while an annual Premium plan will soon cost $40 more at $160. The price changes won't take effect for current PS Plus users on an annual plan until their next renewal date that's on or after November 6th. If you make any changes to your plan between September 6th and then (such as changing tiers), the new pricing will apply. Sony has not announced changes to the monthly ($10 for Essential, $15 for Extra and $18 for Premium) or quarterly ($25 for Essential, $40 for Extra and $50 for Premium) for the time being. It notes that the annual plan is still less expensive than a monthly or quarterly subscription in the long run.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft is Using Malware-like Pop-Ups in Windows 11 To Get People To Ditch Google]]></title>
        <id>https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1550256/microsoft-is-using-malware-like-pop-ups-in-windows-11-to-get-people-to-ditch-google?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1550256/microsoft-is-using-malware-like-pop-ups-in-windows-11-to-get-people-to-ditch-google?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader writes: I thought I had malware on my main Windows 11 machine this weekend. There I was minding my own business in Chrome before tabbing back to a game and wham a pop-up appeared asking me to switch my default search engine to Microsoft Bing in Chrome. Stunningly, Microsoft now thinks it's ok to shove a pop-up in my face above my apps and games just because I dare to use Chrome instead of Microsoft Edge. This isn't a normal notification, either. It didn't appear in the notification center in Windows 11, nor is it connected to the part of Windows 11 that suggests new features to you. It's quite literally a rogue executable file that has somehow appeared in c:\windows\temp\mubstemp and is digitally signed by Microsoft. 

"We are aware of these reports and have paused this notification while we investigate and take appropriate action to address this unintended behavior," says Caitlin Roulston, director of communications, in a statement to The Verge. [...] This isn't Microsoft's first rodeo, either. I'm growing increasingly frustrated by the company's methods of getting people to switch from Google and Chrome to Bing and Edge. Microsoft has been using a variety of prompts for years now, with pop-ups appearing inside Chrome, on the Windows taskbar, and elsewhere. Microsoft has even forced people into Edge after a Windows Update, and regularly presents a full-screen message to switch to Bing and Edge after updates.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FreeBSD Can Now Boot in 25 Milliseconds]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1525238/freebsd-can-now-boot-in-25-milliseconds?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/1525238/freebsd-can-now-boot-in-25-milliseconds?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T15:24:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Replacing a sort algorithm in the FreeBSD kernel has improved its boot speed by a factor of 100 or more... and although it's aimed at a micro-VM, the gains should benefit everyone. From a report: MicroVMs are a hot area of technology R&D in the last half decade or so. The core idea is a re-invention of some of concepts and technology that IBM invented along with the hypervisor in the 1960s: designing OSes specifically to run as guests under another OS. This means building the OS specifically to run inside a VM, and to talk to resources provided by a specific hypervisor rather than to fake hardware. 

This means that the guest OS needs next to no support for real hardware, just VirtIO drivers which talk directly to facilities provided by the host hypervisor. In turn, the hypervisor doesn't have to provide an emulated PCI bus, emulated power management, emulated graphics card, emulated network interface cards, and so on. The result is that the hypervisor itself can be much smaller and simpler. The result of ruthlessly chopping down both the hypervisor, and the OS that runs inside it, is that both ends can be much smaller and simpler. That means that VMs can use much fewer resources, and start up much quicker.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NASA To Demonstrate Laser Communications From Space Station]]></title>
        <id>https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/017243/nasa-to-demonstrate-laser-communications-from-space-station?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/08/30/017243/nasa-to-demonstrate-laser-communications-from-space-station?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SonicSpike shares a report from NASA: In 2023, NASA is sending a technology demonstration known as the Integrated LCRD Low Earth Orbit User Modem and Amplifier Terminal (ILLUMA-T) to the space station. Together, ILLUMA-T and the Laser Communications Relay Demonstration (LCRD), which launched in December 2021, will complete NASA's first two-way, end-to-end laser relay system. With ILLUMA-T, NASA's Space Communications and Navigation (SCaN) program office will demonstrate the power of laser communications from the space station. Using invisible infrared light, laser communications systems send and receive information at higher data rates. With higher data rates, missions can send more images and videos back to Earth in a single transmission. Once installed on the space station, ILLUMA-T will…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Woman's Mystery Illness Turns Out To Be 3-Inch Snake Parasite In Her Brain]]></title>
        <id>https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/232222/womans-mystery-illness-turns-out-to-be-3-inch-snake-parasite-in-her-brain?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/232222/womans-mystery-illness-turns-out-to-be-3-inch-snake-parasite-in-her-brain?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T03:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader quotes a report from Ars Technica: A neurosurgeon in Australia pulled a wriggling 3-inch roundworm from the brain of a 64-year-old woman last year -- which was quite the surprise to the woman's team of doctors and infectious disease experts, who had spent over a year trying to identify the cause of her recurring and varied symptoms. A close study of the extracted worm made clear why the diagnosis was so hard to pin down: the roundworm was one known to infect snakes -- specifically carpet pythons endemic to the area where the woman lived -- as well as the pythons' mammalian prey. The woman is thought to be the first reported human to ever have an infection with this snake-adapted worm, and it is the first time the worm has been found burrowing through a mammalian brain. …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Benevolent Hackers Clear Stalking Spyware From 75,000 Phones]]></title>
        <id>https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/2258208/benevolent-hackers-clear-stalking-spyware-from-75000-phones?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/2258208/benevolent-hackers-clear-stalking-spyware-from-75000-phones?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T01:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[According to TechCrunch, unnamed hackers reportedly breached the spyware firm WebDetetive, deleting device information to protect surveillance victims and denying spyware users new data. Engadget reports: Users of the spyware won't get any new data from their targets. "Because #fuckstalkerware," the hackers wrote in a note obtained by TechCrunch. The WebDetetive breach compromised more than 76,000 devices belonging to customers of the stalkerware, and more than 1.5 gigabytes of data freed from app's servers, according to the hackers.
 
While TechCrunch did not independently confirm the deletion of victim's data from the WebDetetive server, a cache of data shared by the hackers provided a look at what they were able to accomplish. TechCrunch also worked with a nonprofit that logs exposed datasets, DDoSecrets, to verify and analyze the information. Hackers obtained information on customers like IP addresses and devices that they targeted.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple To Buy TSMC's Entire Supply of 3nm Chips For 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://apple.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/2247230/apple-to-buy-tsmcs-entire-supply-of-3nm-chips-for-2023?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://apple.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/2247230/apple-to-buy-tsmcs-entire-supply-of-3nm-chips-for-2023?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T00:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[According to DigiTimes, Apple will receive all TSMC's first-generation 3-nanometer process chips this year for its upcoming devices. MacRumors reports: As early as May, Apple was known to have booked nearly 90% of the Taiwanese pure-play foundry for its upcoming next-gen devices. However, Apple is now projected to take 100% of TSMC's capacity in 2023, due to delays in Intel's wafer needs owing to later modifications to the company's CPU platform design plans. Intel's lack of orders means TSMC's sales of 3nm chips will be significantly lower this year. While TSMC is still expected to experience significant growth in the fourth quarter as it starts mass producing 3nm chips for Apple's needs, they too have been downgraded, according to DigiTimes' industry sources.
 
The report suggests TSMC's 3nm process output may be reduced to 50,000-60,000 wafers monthly in the fourth quarter, down from the 80,000-100,000 units previously anticipated, due to a cutback in Apple's orders. The current monthly output of TSMC's 3nm process is estimated at approximately 65,000 wafers, the outlet's sources said. Apple's upcoming iPhone 15 Pro models are expected to feature the A17 Bionic processor, Apple's first iPhone chip based on TSMC's first-generation 3nm process, also known as N3B. The E3nm technology is said to deliver a 35% power efficiency improvement and 15% faster performance compared to 4nm, which was used to make the A16 Bionic chip for the iPhone 14 Pro and Pro Max.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Launches BigQuery Studio, a New Way To Work With Data]]></title>
        <id>https://developers.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/2118234/google-launches-bigquery-studio-a-new-way-to-work-with-data?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://developers.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/2118234/google-launches-bigquery-studio-a-new-way-to-work-with-data?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T00:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader quotes a report from TechCrunch: Companies increasingly see the value in mining their data for deeper insights. According to a NewVantage survey, 97.6% of major worldwide organizations are focusing investments into big data and AI. But challenges stand in the way of executing big data analytics. One recent poll found that 65% of organizations feel they have "too much" data to analyze. Google's proposed solution is BigQuery Studio, a new service within BigQuery, its fully managed serverless data warehouse, that provides a single experience to edit programming languages including SQL, Python and Spark to run analytics and machine learning workloads at "petabyte scale." BigQuery Studio is available in preview as of this week.
 
"BigQuery Studio is a new experience that rea…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electing New Project Directors]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2023/08/30/electing-new-project-directors.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2023/08/30/electing-new-project-directors.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are launching the process to elect new Project Directors to the Rust Foundation Board of Directors.
As we begin the process, we wanted to spend some time explaining the goals and procedures we will follow.
We will summarize everything here, but if you would like to you can read the official process documentation.
We ask all project members to begin working with their Leadership Council representative to nominate potential Project Directors. See the Candidate Gathering section for more details. Nominations are due by September 15, 2023.
What are Project Directors?
The Rust Foundation Board of Directors has five seats reserved for Project Directors.
These Project Directors serve as representatives of the Rust project itself on the Board.
Like all Directors, the Project Directors are…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Lazy Garbage Nursery Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://taylor.town/lazy-nursery</id>
        <link href="https://taylor.town/lazy-nursery"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you have waste and space, you're wasting space.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>taylor.town</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.5 Kernel Released]]></title>
        <id>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/2112249/linux-65-kernel-released?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/2112249/linux-65-kernel-released?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T23:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ZDNet's Steven Vaughan-Nichols shares what's new in the release of Linux 6.5: The biggest news for servers -- and cloud Linux users -- is AMD Ryzen processors' P-State support. This support should mean better performance and power use across CPU cores. Intel Alder Lake CPUs have also received improved load balancing in a related development. RISC-V architecture fans will be pleased to find Linux now has Advanced Configuration and Power Interface (ACPI) support. ACPI is used in Linux and other operating systems for power management. It's vital for laptops and other battery-powered systems.
 
For better security, people using virtual machines or sandboxes based on Usermode Linux for testing, or running multiple versions of Linux at once, now have Landlock support. Landock is a Linux Security Module that enables applications to sandbox themselves by selecting access rights to directories. It's designed to be used by unprivileged processes while following the system security policy. To make talking with the rest of the world easier, Linux 6.5 now supports USB 4v2. This new USB-C standard will support up to an eye-watering 120Gbps. And while we're still getting used to Wi-Fi 6E, the Wi-Fi Alliance is already working on bringing us Wi-Fi 7. When Wi-Fi 7 arrives, with its theoretical maximum speed of 46Gbps, Linux will be ready. As usual, the new Linux has many more built-in audio and graphics drivers. The Bcachefs filesystem didn't make it into Linux 6.5, notes Vaughan-Nichols. "While the Bcachefs filesystem looks good, there's been a lot of developers fighting about the development process. These personal arguments have led Torvalds to decide not to incorporate Bcachefs into Linux 6.5."
 
Linus Torvalds announced Linux 6.5's delivery in a brief post on August 27.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix Added 2.6 Million US Subscribers In July Despite Password-Sharing Crackdown]]></title>
        <id>https://slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/213220/netflix-added-26-million-us-subscribers-in-july-despite-password-sharing-crackdown?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/213220/netflix-added-26-million-us-subscribers-in-july-despite-password-sharing-crackdown?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T22:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[According to research firm Antenna, Netflix had 2.6 million gross subscriber additions in July. "The company also saw the highest percentage of new sign-ups going to its advertising tier since the $7-a-month offering hit the market last November," reports Deadline. "About 23% of new subscribers opted for the ad tier, a gain of four percentage points over June levels." From the report: The overall July gains represented a 26% downturn from June's record-breaking numbers, but they still show momentum stretching back to the May 23 introduction of paid password sharing in the U.S. From May 24 to 27, Netflix had its four biggest single days of sign-ups in the four-and-a-half years since Antenna has began tracking its subscribers, outpacing even the 2020 Covid boom.
 
The new password scheme followed last fall's debut of the cheaper, ad-supported subscription tier, with the combination of the two providing a potent boost. In the second quarter ending June 30, the company reported that it doubled projections by adding 5.9 million subscribers, reaching 238.3 million worldwide.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sports Leagues Ask US For 'Instantaneous' DMCA Takedowns and Website Blocking]]></title>
        <id>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/2055240/sports-leagues-ask-us-for-instantaneous-dmca-takedowns-and-website-blocking?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/2055240/sports-leagues-ask-us-for-instantaneous-dmca-takedowns-and-website-blocking?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader quotes a report from Ars Technica: Sports leagues are urging the US to require "instantaneous" takedowns of pirated livestreams and new requirements for Internet service providers to block pirate websites. The Digital Millennium Copyright Act of 1998 requires websites to "expeditiously" remove infringing material upon being notified of its existence. But pirated livestreams of sports events often aren't taken down while the events are ongoing, said comments submitted last week by Ultimate Fighting Championship, the National Basketball Association, and National Football League.
 
The "DMCA does not define 'expeditiously,' and OSPs [online service providers] have exploited this ambiguity in the statutory language to delay removing content in response to takedown requests,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reports of the PC's Death Are Greatly Exaggerated, Says IDC]]></title>
        <id>https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/1830233/reports-of-the-pcs-death-are-greatly-exaggerated-says-idc?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/1830233/reports-of-the-pcs-death-are-greatly-exaggerated-says-idc?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T21:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The PC market is expected to return to growth in 2024, according to estimates from IDC analysts. From a report: Still, industry players might want to taper their enthusiasm. PC shipments are forecast to grow 3.7 percent year-on-year to hit 261.4 million units in 2024, putting them above 2018 levels, but not quite on par with 2019 demand. Meanwhile, 2023 is predicted to sink by 13.7 percent to 252 million units. Research manager Jitesh Ubrani called demand "tepid at best" and said 2023 will be the year with the "greatest annual decline in consumer PC shipments since the category's inception." 

IDC recognizes the market still faces challenges including "concerns around the consumer market refresh cycle, businesses pushing device purchases forward, and education budgets that are not rebounding in many markets." Market hesitancy, as always, boils down to uncertainty. For one, processors are seeing what IDC called "some of the biggest shifts in commercial PC history" as AMD market share hit 11 percent in 2022 and Apple pulled in just over 5 percent that year. Apple device sales have been on a decline for multiple quarters now. Q1 2023 saw new Macs plummet more than 40 percent year-on-year, compared to an overall 25-30 percent among PC vendors. The quarter before that saw Apple shipments outperform the PC market as a whole, declining a mere 2.1 percent while other manufacturers experienced 37 percent reductions.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FBI Dismantles a Malware System That Took Millions in Ransom]]></title>
        <id>https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/1826220/fbi-dismantles-a-malware-system-that-took-millions-in-ransom?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/1826220/fbi-dismantles-a-malware-system-that-took-millions-in-ransom?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T20:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The FBI said Tuesday that it has taken down a network of hacked devices responsible for extorting tens of millions of dollars from victims around the world. From a report: US officials described the network known as Qakbot as one of the most notorious "botnets" in the world, referring to computer networks that have been infected with malicious software so that they can be controlled remotely without the owner's knowledge -- often to send phishing emails. These emails can in turn be used to hack into victims' computer systems, which attackers will hold for ransom. 

Qakbot was instrumental in enabling cyberattacks against businesses and critical services around the world, according to US officials, including hits on the San Bernardino County Sheriff's Department and hospitals run by Prospect Medical Group. The latter resulted in the closure of emergency rooms and medical facilities across the US. US officials estimated that, since its creation in 2008, Qakbot had infected around 200,000 computers in the US and 700,000 globally.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google DeepMind Launches Watermarking Tool For AI-Generated Images]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/1823219/google-deepmind-launches-watermarking-tool-for-ai-generated-images?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/1823219/google-deepmind-launches-watermarking-tool-for-ai-generated-images?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google DeepMind has launched a new watermarking tool that labels whether images have been generated with AI. From a report: The tool, called SynthID, will initially be available only to users of Google's AI image generator Imagen, which is hosted on Google Cloud's machine learning platform Vertex. Users will be able to generate images using Imagen and then choose whether to add a watermark or not. The hope is that it could help people tell when AI-generated content is being passed off as real, or help protect copyright. [...] Traditionally images have been watermarked by adding a visible overlay onto them, or adding information into their metadata. But this method is "brittle" and the watermark can be lost when images are cropped, resized, or edited, says Pushmeet Kohli, vice president of research at Google DeepMind. 

SynthID is created using two neural networks. One takes the original image and produces another image that looks almost identical to it, but with some pixels subtly modified. This creates an embedded pattern that is invisible to the human eye. The second neural network can spot the pattern and will tell users whether it detects a watermark, suspects the image has a watermark, or finds that it doesn't have a watermark. Kohli said SynthID is designed in a way that means the watermark can still be detected even if the image is screenshotted or edited -- for example, by rotating or resizing it.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Bitcoin ETF Could Be Coming Soon as Court Rules in Favor of Grayscale Over SEC]]></title>
        <id>https://slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/1816233/first-bitcoin-etf-could-be-coming-soon-as-court-rules-in-favor-of-grayscale-over-sec?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/1816233/first-bitcoin-etf-could-be-coming-soon-as-court-rules-in-favor-of-grayscale-over-sec?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T19:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit has paved the way for bitcoin exchange-traded funds. From a report: On Tuesday, the court sided with Grayscale in a lawsuit against the Securities and Exchange Commission which had denied the company's application to convert the Grayscale Bitcoin Trust to an ETF. The decision could impact other companies that want to create bitcoin ETFs, like BlackRock and Fidelity. A spot bitcoin ETF would be traded through a traditional stock exchange, although the bitcoin would be held by a brokerage, and would allow investors to gain exposure to the world's biggest cryptocurrency without having to own the coin themselves. Many crypto bulls believe that approval of a spot bitcoin ETF will lead to more mainstream institutional adoption. 

Bitcoin, ether and other major cap crypto coins surged on the news, and Coinbase, which is listed as the custodian partner in multiple spot bitcoin ETF applications, was up more than 14% on Tuesday. "The Commission failed to adequately explain why it approved the listing of two bitcoin futures ETPs but not Grayscale's proposed bitcoin ETP," the court said, referring to exchange-traded products. "In the absence of a coherent explanation, this unlike regulatory treatment of like products is unlawful." Grayscale Investments, which manages the world's biggest crypto fund, initiated its lawsuit against the SEC in June 2022 after the agency rejected its application to turn its flagship bitcoin fund, better known by its ticker GBTC, into an ETF. The company decided to pursue the ETF, which would be backed by bitcoin rather than bitcoin derivatives, after the SEC approved ProShares' futures-based bitcoin ETF in October 2021.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The New Google Chat Borrows From Slack, Teams, Discord and Even ChatGPT]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/1731251/the-new-google-chat-borrows-from-slack-teams-discord-and-even-chatgpt?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/1731251/the-new-google-chat-borrows-from-slack-teams-discord-and-even-chatgpt?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T18:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google is making some big changes to Google Chat, its answer to Slack and Microsoft Teams. The messaging app -- aka the product formerly known as hangouts -- is getting a new design, some features that will feel distinctly familiar to Slack and Teams users, and a lot of Google's new Duet AI collaboration tools. From a report: Most of the new features are rolling out later this year and early next, but they add up to a much more useful and competitive Chat platform. Duet is the flagship new feature and potentially a reason for a lot of Workspace users to start using Chat. You can use Duet to search and ask questions about all your stuff in Drive and Gmail and summarize both documents and conversations. You'll also be able to use AI-powered autocorrect in Chat, and thanks to Smart Reply, you might never have to manually talk to your co-workers again. You'll be able to talk to Duet in a one-on-one chat or invoke it in a group chat or a space to help get stuff done. "You essentially have a co-worker who has infinite memory and amazing recall at your fingertips," says Vamsee Jasti, Google's product lead for Chat. 

Outside of the AI integrations, Chat is also getting a facelift. The app has, until now, looked like a fairly barebones messaging app, with a list of conversations on the left and the active chat on the right; now, it's going to have a lot more going on. (And, yes, it will look a lot more like Slack and Teams.) There will be a new home view with all your recent conversations, plus dedicated ways to see all your starred conversations and mentions. For now, everything will be reverse-chronological, but Google says it plans to start more intelligently organizing and ordering things next year. The interface as a whole is getting a bit of cleanup, too, with larger buttons and aesthetics borrowed from Google's Material You design language.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[iFixit Petitions Government For the Right To Fix McDonald's Ice Cream Machines]]></title>
        <id>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/1736232/ifixit-petitions-government-for-the-right-to-fix-mcdonalds-ice-cream-machines?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/1736232/ifixit-petitions-government-for-the-right-to-fix-mcdonalds-ice-cream-machines?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[samleecole writes: A group of right to repair activists and consumer rights advocates are petitioning the Librarian of Congress for the right to hack McDonald's notoriously unreliable McFlurry machines for the purposes of repair, according to a copy of the petition obtained by 404 Media. 

"This is a request to expand the repair exemption for consumer electronic devices to include commercial industrial equipment such as automated building management systems and industrial equipment (i.e. soft serve ice cream machines and other industrial kitchen equipment)," the proposal, written by right to repair group iFixit and the nonprofit Public Knowledge, says. In addition, iFixit got its hands on a Taylor ice cream machine and tore it down in an effort to determine why they are broken so damn often and published a new video showing the process of taking the machine apart and explaining why they're always broken when you want fast food ice cream.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Says Over Half of Generative AI Startups Use Its Cloud]]></title>
        <id>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/1711253/google-says-over-half-of-generative-ai-startups-use-its-cloud?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/08/29/1711253/google-says-over-half-of-generative-ai-startups-use-its-cloud?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T17:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When employees leave Google to join the artificial intelligence startup race, the search giant still has a way to benefit -- by keeping those former workers as cloud customers. From a report: More than half of venture-backed generative AI startups pay for Google's cloud computing platform, Alphabet, Google's parent company, said Tuesday. Of the startups valued at over $1 billion, 70% are Google Cloud customers, and about a third of those are helmed by former employees, including Anthropic, Character.ai and Cohere, the company said. That gives Google a way to extend its influence in the field even when it sheds talent. 

Google's cloud unit, which reported a profit for the first time this year, has emerged as one of the company's best bets for growth as its core search business matures. Google still trails Amazon's AWS and Microsoft's Azure in the market. But startups in the field of generative AI -- programs that can spin up images, text and video from simple prompts -- are increasingly turning to the company, said James Lee, Google Cloud's general manager for startups and AI. "We're seeing strong momentum in our business, and we see Google Cloud as the preferred choice for startups building generative AI," Lee said in an interview. Google Cloud customers have the option to use AI models from Google itself as well as other companies, a degree of flexibility that appeals to startups, Lee said.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Change in Guidance on Committing Lockfiles]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2023/08/29/committing-lockfiles.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2023/08/29/committing-lockfiles.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For years, the Cargo team has encouraged Rust developers to
commit their Cargo.lock file for packages with binaries but not libraries.
We now recommend people
do what is best for their project.
To help people make a decision, we do include some considerations and suggest
committing Cargo.lock as a starting point in their decision making.
To align with that starting point, cargo new will no longer ignore
Cargo.lock for libraries as of nightly-2023-08-24.
Regardless of what decision projects make, we encourage regular
testing against their latest dependencies.
Background
The old guidelines ensured libraries tested their latest dependencies which
helped us keep quality high within Rust's package ecosystem by ensuring issues,
especially backwards compatibility issues,
were quickly found and ad…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leadership Council Membership Changes]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/08/29/leadership-council-membership-changes.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/08/29/leadership-council-membership-changes.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As of today, Khionu Sybiern will no longer be the representative of the Moderation team on the
Leadership Council, and she is also stepping down from the Moderation Team entirely, for personal
reasons. She hopes to return to contributing in the future. Josh Gould will be joining the
Leadership Council as the Moderation Team representative.
We thank Khionu for her extensive time and incredibly important contributions to the Moderation
Team and the Leadership Council. We wish her the best, and that she returns to the Rust community
when she's ready. We thank Josh for being able to fill the Leadership Council role and look forward
to working with them!
We had already begun working on growing the essential Moderation Team before; because of that and
Khio stepping down, we are also pleased to announce that Oliver Scherer (oli-obk) has joined the
Moderation Team. Please join us in welcoming Oli!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Inside Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Eat]]></title>
        <id>https://taylor.town/how-i-eat</id>
        <link href="https://taylor.town/how-i-eat"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm no dietitian, but I've been eating for quite a while.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>taylor.town</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[gzip-ed, streaming uploads from browsers]]></title>
        <id>https://dietcode.io/t/gzip-uploads/</id>
        <link href="https://dietcode.io/t/gzip-uploads/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Can you compress files on your browser before you upload them to your server?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dietcode | Sid's blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seeking help for initial Leadership Council initiatives]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/08/25/leadership-initiatives.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/08/25/leadership-initiatives.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Having not heard any significant disagreement with the first set of proposed priorities,
we are moving ahead with forming subgroups that will work towards defining and
completing the work needed to drive these forward. We plan to re-assess
priorities regularly, but for now these are our main work items (in no
particular order). We have some initial volunteers who will be pushing these
initiatives forward, but for all of these we are also looking for support from
any interested people. Please reach out on Zulip in #council if
you'd like to help out with any of these in some capacity, or to the initial
volunteers called out here.
Establishing plans for how to strengthen the moderation team (i.e., 2 is not a sustainable number) and strengthen moderation policies.

Josh Gould is leading, with support from Eric Holk. Their top priority is finding additional moderators and forming a contingent moderator team.
Figuring out the "shape" of the Rust Project. The Leadership Council needs to reflect the will of the Rust Project so it is important to know who that includes.

Eric Huss is leading, with support from Jack Huey. They're working on defining the initial set of priorities here now.
Documenting and improving processes for interaction with the Rust Foundation including formalising the role of project directors in this process (the trademark policy process may be part of this).

We are looking for someone to help lead this initiative, with support from Mark Rousskov and Ryan Levick, two of the current  project directors. One of the proposed first concrete deliverables might be working towards a path forward on the trademark issue, using that as a stepping stone to defining broader policies. We're intentionally looking for someone not directly involved previously to help give an outside perspective as the lead.
Please reach out if you're interested in helping!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Inside Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Admiration makes the team]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/jason/admiration-makes-the-team-a26570c3</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/jason/admiration-makes-the-team-a26570c3"/>
        <updated>2023-08-24T22:40:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When people talk about great teams, they'll talk about hard work, trust, respect, looking out for one another, etc. All good things.
But there's one quality amongst teammates on great teams that often goes unrecognized by all but the most astute organizational observers: Admiration.
Great teams are made of people who *admire* one another's talents, skills, character, and contributions. Great teams are mutual admiration societies who get to work together.
Admiration is the critical, silent variable in the powerful formula that equals exceptional teamwork.

-Jason]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Fried</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Technology Strategy for Emerging Technologies and Markets]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/creating-integrated-tech-strategy.html#RespondingToTheEverChangingFuture</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/creating-integrated-tech-strategy.html#RespondingToTheEverChangingFuture"/>
        <updated>2023-08-24T13:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sarah Taraporewalla completes her study of building a
     technology strategy that's integrated with strategic business interests.
     This final strategic direction considers the ever-changing future,
     suggesting lines of inquiry to consider the impact of new
     technologies, market trends, and broader social-political changes. 
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Rust 1.72.0]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2023/08/24/Rust-1.72.0.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2023/08/24/Rust-1.72.0.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Rust team is happy to announce a new version of Rust, 1.72.0. Rust is a programming language empowering everyone to build reliable and efficient software.
If you have a previous version of Rust installed via rustup, you can get 1.72.0 with:
rustup update stable

If you don't have it already, you can get rustup from the appropriate page on our website, and check out the detailed release notes for 1.72.0 on GitHub.
If you'd like to help us out by testing future releases, you might consider updating locally to use the beta channel (rustup default beta) or the nightly channel (rustup default nightly). Please report any bugs you might come across!
What's in 1.72.0 stable
Rust reports potentially useful cfg-disabled items in errors
You can conditionally enable Rust code using cfg, such as to…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cargo changes how arrays in config are merged]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/08/24/cargo-config-merging.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/08/24/cargo-config-merging.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cargo will be changing the order of merged configuration arrays, and we are looking for people to help test this change and provide feedback.
When an array in Cargo's configuration is defined in multiple places, the elements are merged together. The order that the elements were merged was inconsistent with how other configuration types were merged together, and was not working as expected.
The new merging order will match the precedence order of non-array configuration, with higher-precedence configuration being placed later in the array.
In the case of build.rustflags, this resolves the confusing situation where higher precedence flags (in a project's config.toml) are overridden with lower precedence flags (in the global $CARGO_HOME, for example).
This may result in behavior changes if a …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Inside Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[So Long, Twitter and Reddit]]></title>
        <id>https://andrewkelley.me/post/goodbye-twitter-reddit.html</id>
        <link href="https://andrewkelley.me/post/goodbye-twitter-reddit.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-23T22:05:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So Long, Twitter and Reddit
It's been over three years since my last blog post. I think that
the website code started to feel like it had bitrotted, and so making new blog
posts became onerous. But I've taken the time to redo this website
using Zig, so it's quite easy to add blog
posts now, and plus I added
dark mode.
Twitter
Over the past few years I amassed a healthy number of followers on Twitter by posting
screenshots, demos, and small progress updates for the Zig programming language. It
felt good to gain an audience and have my perspective and efforts weighed more heavily in
the court of public opinion.
However, I always knew that it would need to end. It's not really possible to use Twitter
without at least a little bit of doomscrolling, and that activity took a toll on me emotional…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Kelley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scatter]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/jason/scatter-8a4a1e4a</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/jason/scatter-8a4a1e4a"/>
        <updated>2023-08-23T19:30:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scatter.


Scatter is the silent killer at work.


Scatter is tools siloed by teams.


Scatter is multiple apps to do one thing.


Scatter is doing the same thing at the same time in multiple places.


Scatter is asking around rather than doing it right now.


Scatter is pulling people off this to jump on that.


Scatter is wondering where something is rather than knowing where it lives.


Scatter is repeating yourself.


Scatter is dependencies.


Scatter is looking but not paying attention.


Scatter is intracompany fiefdoms defending themselves.


Scatter is attempted multitasking.


Scatter is waiting around for something else to happen first.


Scatter is multiple monitors.


Scatter is being busy without making progress.


Scatter is principles on the wall that no one believes.


Scatter is a backlog of ideas you'll never get to.


Scatter are far off promises you made because it was easier than saying no.


Scatter is looking back at your day and wondering where it all went.


Scatter is conceptual engines burning in opposite directions.
Scatter is a huge, invisible liability you'll never see on your balance sheet.


Scatter is what scatter does.
Scatter has its place as long as it's not the steady state.


-Jason]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Fried</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demo Front-End: A front-end application to test and explore an API]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/demo-front-end.html</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/demo-front-end.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-23T14:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many software teams create services exposed as APIs, designed to be
     consumed by other software and thus without any user-interface. Such
     services are hard to demonstrate, as they effectively just dump pages of
     JSON. A demo front-end is a simple user-interface just used to
     manipulate such an API. Matteo Vaccari describes how and
     why to build one - showing its usefulness both in explaining the
     API's capabilities to stakeholders and to help client developers explore
     how to interact with the API.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strategic Directions supporting the people]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/creating-integrated-tech-strategy.html#SupportingThePeople</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/creating-integrated-tech-strategy.html#SupportingThePeople"/>
        <updated>2023-08-22T15:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Having a robust digital talent strategy is a competitive advantage in
     today’s fiercely competitive market. This enables businesses to have the
     right talent and have the right competencies to meet current and future
     demand to meet business goals or to stay on track for digital
     transformation aspirations. Sarah Taraporewalla continues
     her article on how to create an integrated business and technology strategy
     by looking at questions raised by two strategic directions that
     support people: culture and internal systems.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bottlenecks of Scaleups #05: Resilience and Observability]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/bottlenecks-of-scaleups/05-resilience-and-observability.html</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/bottlenecks-of-scaleups/05-resilience-and-observability.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-22T14:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here is a new article in the bottlenecks of scaleups series, looking at
     resilience and observability. Startups tend to only address resilience when
     their systems are already down, often taking a very reactive approach. For
     a scaleup, excessive system downtime represents a significant
     bottleneck to the organization, both from the effort expended on
     restoring function and also from the impact of customer dissatisfaction.
     Punit Lad and Carl Nygard explain that to
     move past this, resilience needs to be built into the business objectives,
     which will influence the architecture, design, product management, and even
     governance of business systems. 
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[56% of McNugget Carbon is Corn]]></title>
        <id>https://taylor.town/carbon-nuggets</id>
        <link href="https://taylor.town/carbon-nuggets"/>
        <updated>2023-08-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Corn isotopes everywhere! Has science gone too far?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>taylor.town</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[1.72.0 pre-release testing]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/08/21/1.72.0-prerelease.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/08/21/1.72.0-prerelease.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 1.72.0 pre-release is ready for testing. The release is scheduled for
August 24. Release notes can be found here.
You can try it out locally by running:
RUSTUP_DIST_SERVER=https://dev-static.rust-lang.org rustup update stable

The index is https://dev-static.rust-lang.org/dist/2023-08-21/index.html.
You can leave feedback on the internals thread.
The release team is also thinking about changes to our pre-release process:
we'd love your feedback on this GitHub issue.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Inside Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm a Coin Boy, Too]]></title>
        <id>https://taylor.town/coin-boys</id>
        <link href="https://taylor.town/coin-boys"/>
        <updated>2023-08-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My crystal ball shattered in my twenties, but the coin offers faith to the faithless.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>taylor.town</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to do a successful Hacker News launch]]></title>
        <id>https://lucasfcosta.com/2023/08/21/hn-launch.html</id>
        <link href="https://lucasfcosta.com/2023/08/21/hn-launch.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-20T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When it comes to writing, the #1 question I usually get asked is how do I get so many HN front pages with this blog.
This week, Layerform got to the front page for the first time too, and I got asked that question another bunch of times.


I decided to write this document explaining how to do it so I can send people a link now.
As a heads-up, there is only one hack: making something people want (to upvote).
Also, keep in mind this is all public information on how HackerNews works. There’s no magic here.
Make your title direct and specific. Get straight to the point. Generic or vague titles do not perform well. Salesy titles perform even worse. Don’t worry about adding some technical detail. Explain what you do precisely.
    
Good example: Show HN: Layerform – Open-source development envir…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucas F. Costa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TDD with GitHub Copilot]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/exploring-gen-ai.html#memo-06</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/exploring-gen-ai.html#memo-06"/>
        <updated>2023-08-17T18:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Thoughtworks, we are strong practitioners of Test Driven Development (TDD).
     Naturally this leads to the question of how generative AI can help with
     this technique. Paul Sobocinski writes a brief memo
     explaining how some of our teams have used TDD with GitHub
     Copilot. As ever, co-pilot can't be relied on to fly the plane, but
     can suggest some useful ideas for the red and green steps. It isn't
     very helpful for the all-important refactoring step.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final parts of the cost bottleneck of scaleups]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/bottlenecks-of-scaleups/04-costs.html#ReviewAndGovernTechnologyPortfolio</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/bottlenecks-of-scaleups/04-costs.html#ReviewAndGovernTechnologyPortfolio"/>
        <updated>2023-08-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sofia Tania  and  Stefania
       Stefansdottir complete their examination of how to overcome the
       bottleneck that costs impose on a scaleup. In this final installment,
       they look at how to review and govern the technology portfolio,
       optimize rates, and provide a general view of cost efficiency initiatives
       during the life-cycle of a scaleup.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strategic directions: minimizing risk and being data driven]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/creating-integrated-tech-strategy.html#risk</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/creating-integrated-tech-strategy.html#risk"/>
        <updated>2023-08-16T19:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Time for two more strategic directions from Sarah
     Taraporewalla. These look at the questions that need to be investigated when
     reducing cost, minimizing operation risk, and enabling data-driven decision
     making.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bottlenecks of Scaleups Webinar: Sep 7 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://www.thoughtworks.com/about-us/events/webinars/scaling-bottlenecks--technology-mistakes-every-growing-startup-m</id>
        <link href="https://www.thoughtworks.com/about-us/events/webinars/scaling-bottlenecks--technology-mistakes-every-growing-startup-m"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T18:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join Tim Cochran and Rickey Zachery on Thursday, September 7th 1-2pm EST
     for a webinar on Bottlenecks of
     Scaleups: Technology mistakes every growing startup makes. They researched
     Thoughtwork's portfolio to analyze why companies struggle to scale,
     spanning across Technology, People, and Product. Covering areas such as
     experimentation culture, overcomplicated architectures, onboarding,
     developer productivity, product and engineering collaboration, and cost
     efficiency.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strategic directions to build a strong foundation]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/creating-integrated-tech-strategy.html#BuildingAStrongFoundation</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/creating-integrated-tech-strategy.html#BuildingAStrongFoundation"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T14:16:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Any business that wants to grow needs to be built on strong and stable
     foundations. While these strategic directions are often familiar to
     technical folks it's important that the improvements to engineering align
     with the themes that resonate with the rest of the organization.
     Sarah Taraporewalla illustrates how this appears with two
     strategic directions that consider improvements in efficiency and quality.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Actions to sustain cost control for scaleups]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/bottlenecks-of-scaleups/04-costs.html#SustainPhase</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/bottlenecks-of-scaleups/04-costs.html#SustainPhase"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T14:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When scaling up, getting costs under control is vital to stabilizing
       financial health. But as a weight-loss expert might say, the key to
       long-term health is to do things that promote a sustainable lifestyle.
       Sofia Tania  and  Stefania
       Stefansdottir now move on to begin to describe these
       initiatives: federated accountability, visibility, and nudges
       towards better financial discipline.
       
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thinking about functional programming]]></title>
        <id>http://notes.eatonphil.com/2023-08-15-thinking-about-functional-programming.html</id>
        <link href="http://notes.eatonphil.com/2023-08-15-thinking-about-functional-programming.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Someone on Discord asked about how to learn functional programming.
The question and my initial tweet on the subject prompted an
interesting
discussion
with Shriram
Krishnamurthi and other folks.
So here's a slightly more thought out exploration.
And just for backstory sake: I spent a few years a while
ago programming in
Standard ML and I wrote
a chunk of a Scheme
  implementation. I'm not an expert, but I have a bit of background.
Hey, this is a free opinion.
Concepts from functional programming
When people talk about functional programming, I think of a few key
choices you can make while programming:
Immutability by default
(Tail) recursion by default
First-class functions (and the suite of tools that go along with it. e.g. map, reduce/fold)
And if you have experience as a programmer, yo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Notes on software development</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thinking about functional programming]]></title>
        <id>http://notes.eatonphil.com/2023-08-15-thinking-about-functional-programming.html</id>
        <link href="http://notes.eatonphil.com/2023-08-15-thinking-about-functional-programming.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Someone on Discord asked about how to learn functional programming.
The question and my initial tweet on the subject prompted an
interesting
discussion
with Shriram
Krishnamurthi and other folks.
So here's a slightly more thought out exploration.
And just for backstory sake: I spent a few years a while
ago programming in
Standard ML and I wrote
a chunk of a Scheme
  implementation. I'm not an expert, but I have a bit of background.
Hey, this is a free opinion.
Concepts from functional programming
When people talk about functional programming, I think of a few key
choices you can make while programming:
Immutability by default
(Tail) recursion by default
First-class functions (and the suite of tools that go along with it. e.g. map, reduce/fold)
And if you have experience as a programmer, yo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Notes on software development</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How would you like ChatGPT to respond?]]></title>
        <id>https://taylor.town/chatgpt-custom</id>
        <link href="https://taylor.town/chatgpt-custom"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Emulate clear writers like Steinbeck, Hemingway, Orwell.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>taylor.town</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We will miss Stefan Tilkov]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/202308-stefan-tilkov.html</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/202308-stefan-tilkov.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T18:58:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are saddened today to learn of the passing of Stefan Tilkov. We’ve met Stefan several times at workshops and conferences and always enjoyed his good company and insightful views. He advocated many of the things that we and our colleagues support - and as well as skillfully explaining these ideas, he also backed them up with concrete experience from his work. We shall really miss his wise contributions online, and regret that we won’t get the chance to chat with him again. We offer our condolences to his family, friends, and colleagues at INNOQ.
Birgitta Boeckeler
Erik Dörnenburg
Neal Ford
Martin Fowler
James Lewis
Rebecca Parsons
Daniel Terhorst-North]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[gpt'day mate]]></title>
        <id>https://taylor.town/gpt-day-mate</id>
        <link href="https://taylor.town/gpt-day-mate"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Please prioritize today's task list.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>taylor.town</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Difficult and complex]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/jorge/difficult-and-complex-8b3bcc2f</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/jorge/difficult-and-complex-8b3bcc2f"/>
        <updated>2023-08-11T11:10:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is complex and there is difficult, they are not the same. 


Being able to run a marathon is very difficult. But what you have to do to prepare is simple. A small sheet of paper is enough to describe the steps. You will need tremendous effort and discipline - so it’s hard - but it is simple.


Software development is different: it is also complex.


A common theme in my articles on how we do Rails at 37signals is how facing software development with rigid recipes is naive and counterproductive. A good example is services: using a service for everything is a simple idea; applying domain-driven design and object orientation is not. Another manifestation is banning techniques because they can be harmful: concerns, accessing the database from models, callbacks, globals, etc. Ironically, the alternative critics usually recommend for those is using services.


In software, you must take a Babylonian body of knowledge, combine it with your own experience, and apply the result to make countless daily decisions. And of all this for a problem you can’t understand without solving it first. Rigidity doesn’t work, and – because this is a game of intricate complexity – it yields more harm than benefit. You need to embrace nuance.


Mind the recipes you follow.

---
jorgemanrubia.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jorge Manrubia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning to accept defeat against reality]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/dhh/learning-to-accept-defeat-against-reality-141fb093</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/learning-to-accept-defeat-against-reality-141fb093"/>
        <updated>2023-08-11T10:53:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A great many smart people terminably hamper their ability to better understand the world by refusing to accept defeat when reality proves them wrong. Armed with an intellect that's at once both too proud to recognize it's own failings and cunningly capable of producing sophisticated excuses, they're adapt at spotting this failing in others but not in themselves.
You see this all the time in the realm of public policy. Someone presents a plausible thesis on how to deal with a given problem. They drum up support for an attempt that follows their ideas, but when the attempt is defeated by reality, they can't retreat, and become stuck trying to defend the path in ever-more creative yet ludicrous ways.
Watch the cadre of "harm reduction" activists attempt to defend the increasingly decrepit sta…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chloe is a listener]]></title>
        <id>https://taylor.town/listener</id>
        <link href="https://taylor.town/listener"/>
        <updated>2023-08-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chloe has no stories of her own, and she doesn't need them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>taylor.town</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First stage of reducing costs for a scaleup]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/bottlenecks-of-scaleups/04-costs.html#ReducePhase</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/bottlenecks-of-scaleups/04-costs.html#ReducePhase"/>
        <updated>2023-08-10T15:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When scaleups need to start working on cost efficiency, our experience
       is that they need to form a cost optimization team to work on the
       immediate steps that are needed. In this installment Sofia and
       Stefania describe how to understand the primary cost drivers,
       together with the levers to get them under control. 
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech strategy for new customer segments and inorganic growth]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/creating-integrated-tech-strategy.html#expand-segments</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/creating-integrated-tech-strategy.html#expand-segments"/>
        <updated>2023-08-10T14:12:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sarah Taraporewalla moves on to the remaining two
     strategic directions that are part of growing the business.
     Expanding into new customer segments can introduce new operational
     processes or channels. Inorganic growth (eg acquisitions and mergers) needs
     an understanding of the drivers of increased value and the long term
     expectation (eg merge or keep separate and divest) for the business unit. 
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coding assistants do not replace pair programming]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/exploring-gen-ai.html#memo-05</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/exploring-gen-ai.html#memo-05"/>
        <updated>2023-08-10T13:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In her 5th memo about exploring GenAI for software development,
      Birgitta Böckeler answers the frequently asked question if
      coding assistants are making the practice of Pair Programming
      obsolete. Spoiler alert: They don't.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turns out nobody cared about panel gaps]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/dhh/turns-out-nobody-cared-about-panel-gaps-914127d5</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/turns-out-nobody-cared-about-panel-gaps-914127d5"/>
        <updated>2023-08-10T11:55:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the most fascinating aspects of Tesla's rise to dominance has been how they discarded many of the traditional values of car making. While the rest of the industry was stuck competing on the size of their panel gaps, and other aspects of precision and quality assembly, Tesla didn't even show up to participate. Their cars are legendary for being delivered with shoddy paint jobs, rattling interiors, and even mismatched doors. But it just didn't matter! Consumers voted with their wallets for poorly built EVs because well-built gas-powered cars were deemed irrelevant in comparison.
There's tremendous wisdom for product makers of all kinds in this lesson. It's the epitome of Blue Ocean Strategy. To find a breakthrough angle in commerce, it's as important to decide where you will not compe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating an integrated business and technology strategy]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/creating-integrated-tech-strategy.html</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/creating-integrated-tech-strategy.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T10:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My colleague Sarah Taraporewalla describes an approach
     to building technology strategy that challenges the convention. It starts
     by identifying the overall strategic directions that the organization is
     considering, and using common aspects of these directions to indicate the
     investigations needed for the organization to understand the technology
     implications raised by that strategic change. This first
     installment looks at two of these directions: expanding the business
     by creating complementary products, and expanding the business into new
     markets and regions. 
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The curing value of creation]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/dhh/the-curing-value-of-creation-98736f9f</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/the-curing-value-of-creation-98736f9f"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T09:52:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's hard not to see your spirits lifted when you're part of bringing something to life. Be that a product, an organization, or a community, or all three at once. Like exercise, it's one of those rare avenues of human endeavor that almost invariably will make anyone feel better. And, also like exercise, the hard part is getting started when you need it the most!
That's the curious chasm between knowledge and action. As much as you may know that regular, high-intensity training of the body does wonders for the mind, summoning the motivation to follow through with a commitment to working out only gets harder and harder the more you need it. I've had periods in my life where being removed from meaningful acts of creation felt just the same way.
Those periods were especially depressing when they felt like a simulacra of creation. Being in a situation designed to mimic the motions of making, but bereft of any meaningful progress towards that end. The pretending of purpose. The appearance of collaboration. Without any thrust towards completion.
And just as how getting a positive streak of accomplishment going provides its own momentum to keep at it, so too does a negative streak of performative busyness. It pulls you back into the comfort of the mental couch, and hands you the bag of chips to soothe your nagging sense of uselessness. For every day you stay there, the harder it is to get up, so best to muster everything you got to escape the dulling inertia now.
Make something. Participate in something. Engage with someone. All of it might feel as unnatural as strapping on those running shoes after too long of a break, but once you're back to creating, the energy comes by itself.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Et tu, Zoom?]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/dhh/et-tu-zoom-b90a0a0a</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/et-tu-zoom-b90a0a0a"/>
        <updated>2023-08-07T16:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The corporate cause for return-to-office just claimed its perhaps most ironic victim: Zoom! The company that literally lives to sell us all on the wonders of remote collaboration wants its own people back into the office again. Which I guess is just a regression to the mean of productivity tool makers failing to believe their own marketing, but it's a bit sad none the less.
Not the least because this push for return-to-office has now been proven completely safe for large tech corporations. Thanks to the mixture of mass layoffs earlier this year and the now numerous proclamations that remote-first is over at the majority of big companies. Safety in sentiment, safety in numbers.
This is an opportunistic squeeze, because what's most tech workers supposed to do? The option of simply hopping to another company has been severely limited. Outside the small realm of AI experts, most other domains just aren't anywhere nearly as contested in hiring as they once were. So this is happening now because it can happen now.
I just hope that people who really did enjoy that remote work-lifetyle don't forget what it was like. The balance of power will presumably turn around one day again, and when it does, voting with your feet will be an option again.
Until then, I suspect that the likes of Shopify, Automattic, and other stalwart defenders of remote work will continue to see their openings become increasingly oversubscribed. Just like we've had at 37signals for going on two decades.
Remote work might be receding, but it's simply too compelling an option for too many to ever disappear. The long-term trend line ain't going anywhere.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2022 Annual Rust Survey Results]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2023/08/07/Rust-Survey-2023-Results.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2023/08/07/Rust-Survey-2023-Results.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello, Rustaceans!
For the 6th year in a row, the Rust Project conducted a survey on the Rust programming language, with participation from project maintainers, contributors, and those generally interested in the future of Rust. This edition of the annual State of Rust Survey opened for submissions on December 5 and ran until December 22, 2022.
First, we'd like to thank you for your patience on these long delayed results. We hope to identify a more expedient and sustainable process going forward so that the results come out more quickly and have even more actionable insights for the community.
The goal of this survey is always to give our wider community a chance to express their opinions about the language we all love and help shape its future. We’re grateful to those of you who took the …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>