<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://ririyad.github.io/rssreads/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-07-30T01:11:14.424Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ririyad.github.io/rssreads/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://ririyad.github.io/rssreads/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring Gen AI - Three versions of a median]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/exploring-gen-ai.html#median---a-tale-in-three-functions</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/exploring-gen-ai.html#median---a-tale-in-three-functions"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T14:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Birgitta Böckeler continues her explorations in using
     LLMs, this time by asking GitHub Copilot to write a median
     function. It gave her three suggestions to choose from. The
     experience shows you still have to know what you're doing when asking LLMs
     to write code, since the LLM's programming skills are often rather flawed.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X marks the motivated reasoning]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/dhh/x-marks-the-motivated-reasoning-13450584</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/x-marks-the-motivated-reasoning-13450584"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T09:16:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve lost track of all the things that Musk has done to Twitter that ought to have brought it down by now. Scarcely a month goes by without some action triggering the incessant bells of doom, ringing from the bellies of bloviating ding dongs. And the ringing seemingly never stops long enough to allow for some basic contemplation or correction, as reality wrecks another prediction of peril.


But the obsession with all things Elon is so strong that there’s no room or time for introspection of any kind. It’s just on to the next faux outrage of tomorrow. Make sure you never miss a chance to be an expert on social media, advertising, team building, economics, or branding so you can tell the world’s most successful entrepreneur what a total idiot he’s being, and how much smarter, wiser, and kin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring Gen AI - The toolchain]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/exploring-gen-ai.html#the-toolchain</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/exploring-gen-ai.html#the-toolchain"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T14:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My colleague Birgitta Böckeler has long been one of our senior
     technology leaders in Germany. She's now moved into a new role coordinating
     our work with Generative AI and its effect of software delivery practices.
     She's decided to publish her exploration in a series of memos. The first
     memo looks at the current toolchain for LLMs, categorizing them by what
     tasks they help with, how we interact with the LLM, and where they come from.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working remotely is a competitive hiring advantage again]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/dhh/working-remotely-is-a-competitive-hiring-advantage-again-c182250e</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/working-remotely-is-a-competitive-hiring-advantage-again-c182250e"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T07:44:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As more and more companies, especially large ones, have started demanding remote workers return to the office, the competitive hiring advantage for remote-first companies is back. And it's even bigger than before the pandemic, now that so many workers have had a taste of what life can be like when you don't have to commute to the office. This is great news for smaller companies and startups in particular.
Let's face it, if you're trying to compete for talent with the likes of Google or Apple, you need all the help you can get, and these companies forcing everyone back into an office might just be your biggest lift. Because for quite a few people, working remotely or not has become the defining characteristic of a job. To the point where many remote workers won't even consider a position th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bliki: TeamTopologies]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TeamTopologies.html</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TeamTopologies.html"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T13:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Any large software effort, such as the software estate for a large
    company, requires a lot of people - and whenever you have a lot of people
    you have to figure out how to divide them into effective teams. Forming
    Business Capability Centric teams helps software efforts to
    be responsive to customers’ needs, but the range of skills required often
    overwhelms such teams. Team Topologies is a model
    for describing the organization of software development teams,
    developed by Matthew Skelton and Manuel Pais. It defines four forms
    of teams and three modes of team
    interactions. The model encourages healthy interactions that allow 
    business-capability centric teams to flourish in their task of providing a
    steady flow of valuable software.
The primary kind o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bliki: TwoPizzaTeam]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TwoPizzaTeam.html</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TwoPizzaTeam.html"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T13:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A two-pizza team is a small team
  that fully supports software for a particular business capability. The term
  became popular as it used to describe how Amazon organized their software staff.
The name suggests the most obvious aspect of such teams, their size. The
  name comes from the principle that the team should no larger than can be fed
  with two pizzas. (Although we are talking about American Pizzas here, which
  seemed alarmingly huge when I first encountered them over here.) Keeping a
  team small keeps it cohesive, forming tight working relationships. Typically I
  hear this means such teams are about 5-8 people, although my experience
  suggests that the upper limit is somewhere about 15.
Although the name focuses solely on the size, just as important is the
  team's focus. A …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pick promise over proof]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/dhh/pick-promise-over-proof-756604d3</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/pick-promise-over-proof-756604d3"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T08:49:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After hiring people for twenty years, I've come to accept that it's impossible to know up front what someone is truly capable of. Sure, we try our best to make good, educated guesses during the hiring process, and this is why asking finalists to do sample work projects is so crucial. But it still remains just guessing, and the truth doesn't emerge until you afford the hire a full attempt on a real project.
That's why I'm such a fan of starting new employees in the deep end. Putting them to work on a real project right away. But this is only half the commitment you ought to make to their potential.
It's just as important to retain the possibility of rapid progression by continuing to test their promise against harder and bigger challenges. I can't tell you the number of times I've been posi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[July 2023 Leadership Council Update]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/07/25/leadership-council-update.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/07/25/leadership-council-update.html"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello again from the Rust Leadership Council. In our first blog post, we laid out several immediate goals for the council and promised to report back on their progress. It has been about a month since our first update so we wanted to share how it's going and what we're working on now.
Accomplishments so far
In our first post, we wrote:
In the coming weeks we will be establishing the basic infrastructure for the group, including creating a plan for regular meetings and a process for raising agenda items, setting up a team repository, and ultimately completing the transition from the former Rust leadership structures.
We have made progress on each of these things.
For the last month we have been holding weekly meetings and will continue to do so for at least the next month. In the long term,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Inside Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clear the barnacles]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/dhh/clear-the-barnacles-b9558830</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/clear-the-barnacles-b9558830"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T08:42:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The easiest way to squander your focus is by paying attention to a million inconsequential things at once. These little mental barnacles add up in imperceptible ways until you suddenly feel like you're getting nowhere, no matter how hard you push. You must keep scrubbing your mind clear of such attention-sapping colonies to remain capable of making smooth, swift progress.
These barnacles can accumulate from middling marketing initiatives, process theatre, and tolerance for mediocre performance. All individually presenting as more hassle to deal with than to dismiss, but combined killing the efficiency and focus on progress.
But they can also be things that actually appears to be working well enough, just not up to the bar of your very best. Those are the tricky ones. The base hits, the modest accomplishments, the things you might even have celebrated once. The past darlings.
It just doesn't matter. You can't keep stuffing your head with ever more things to pay partial attention to every month and expect to keep a clear eye on the horizon and the future. There's only room for so much.
The hardest part about this is not to wait until it's too much, until the drag is actually there. Keep your mind below carrying capacity, such that there's room for serendipity, at all times.
In short, be decisive about what you'll no longer do. Summon your inner Jack Welch to cut at least the bottom 10% of the stuff dragging your attention every few months or so.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[crates.io Postmortem: Broken Crate Downloads]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/07/21/crates-io-postmortem.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/07/21/crates-io-postmortem.html"/>
        <updated>2023-07-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[(based on https://www.atlassian.com/incident-management/postmortem/templates)
Summary
On 2023-07-20 between 12:17 and 12:30 UTC all crate downloads from crates.io were broken due to a deployment that contained a bug in the download URL generation.
During this time we had an average of 4.71K requests per second to crates.io, resulting in about 3.7M failed requests, including the retry attempts from cargo.
The incident was noticed by the developer triggering the production deployment after seeing elevated request-per-second numbers in our monitoring dashboard after the deployment. At this point the root cause for the elevated numbers was not clear yet, but a community member notified the developer via Zulip.
Immediately after the notification, the broken deployment was rolled back to the pre…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Inside Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effective > Productive]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/jason/effective-productive-acfa210d</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/jason/effective-productive-acfa210d"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T17:31:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So much talk about hacking productivity these days. There’s an endless stream of methodologies and tools promising to make you more productive. But more productive at what?
Productivity is for machines, not for people. There’s nothing meaningful about packing some number of work units into some amount of time or squeezing more into less.
Machines can work 24/7; humans can’t.
When people focus on productivity, they end up focusing on being busy. Filling every moment with something to do. And there’s always more to do!
We don’t believe in busyness at Basecamp. We believe in effectiveness. How little can we do? How much can we cut out? Instead of adding to-dos, we add to-don’ts.
Being productive is about occupying your time—filling your schedule to the brim and getting as much as you can. Being effective is about finding more of your time unoccupied and open for other things besides work. Time for leisure, time for family and friends. Or time for doing absolutely nothing.
Yes, it’s perfectly okay to have nothing to do. Or, better yet, nothing worth doing. If you’ve only got three hours of work to do on a given day, then stop. Don’t fill your day with five more just to stay busy or feel productive. Not doing something that isn’t worth doing is a wonderful way to spend your time.
——
via It Doesn't Have to Be Crazy at Work
https://basecamp.com/books/calm

-Jason]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Fried</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don't lose your unreasonable sense of urgency]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/dhh/don-t-lose-your-unreasonable-sense-of-urgency-b381699c</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/don-t-lose-your-unreasonable-sense-of-urgency-b381699c"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T15:33:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting anything new off the ground usually requires a tremendous amount of urgency. It's hard to launch something  from nothing into reality without being incredibly impatient for progress. Thus most founders begin 🎶Their Journey🎶 sprinting from one pressing problem to the next in rapid succession to achieve their lift off. But reaching escape velocity doesn't guarantee you'll keep going, unless you retain the propulsion from an unreasonable sense of urgency.
Yet the irony of being successful in business is that it'll invariably attract smart people who can tell you all the good reasons for why you can no longer go as quickly as you once did. Why it's actually natural, perhaps even good, that a company ten or a hundred times the size of what it was when it first became successful now has to travel at half the pace to be prudent.
Don't listen too closely. Not because they'll be wrong in any narrow technical sense, but because they're wrong in the broad directional sense. The risk of succumbing to the rigor mortis of success is usually far greater than the risk of making a mistake by not considering and mitigating all possible bad outcomes up front.
It's the risk of mandating everyone put on a bike helmet, only to realize that doing so means fewer people will bike, leading to worse health outcomes for all. Being obsessive about specific, short-term risks often sits in opposition to worrying about fuzzy, long-term risks.
And nobody will be as motivated as a founder to inject risk into the business. Sticking with an unreasonable sense of urgency undoubtedly comes with clear and immediate risks. But giving up on it with even worse, less defined ones.
So don't give up. Every company needs to have someone asking why we can't launch next Monday instead of next month. Willing to accept and underwrite the risks needed to make it happen. And with a stomach for occasionally being wrong, eating the loss, but keep playing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There's no rebound in sight for unprofitable SaaS]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/dhh/there-s-no-rebound-in-sight-for-unprofitable-saas-49a06b4d</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/there-s-no-rebound-in-sight-for-unprofitable-saas-49a06b4d"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T17:42:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anyone reviewing their S&P 500 retirement fund these days will do so with a broader smile than last year. The market as a whole is up, and if you're in the whole market, you're benefitting. But all of that upside, basically, belongs to just a handful of mega tech companies. 
This is not a general turn-around, and it's barely a turn-around at all for the unprofitable SaaS companies that saw their bubble burst last year. In software, only cash spigots like Apple and Microsoft are able to set fresh all-time highs. Investors who bought into money pits like Asana, Monday, or Smartsheet are still likely to be in despair over their evaporated values.
  
      
        

  
(Analysis by Coatue from 6/30/2023.)
This is an important change from the marathon bull run that lifted all tech businesses, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How platform teams get stuff done]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/platform-teams-stuff-done.html</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/platform-teams-stuff-done.html"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T14:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Platform teams have a unique reliance on other teams to ensure adoption
     of their platform - getting code changes into other teams' codebase is
     critical to their success. Pete Hodgson structures how
     platform teams collaborate into phases
     of migration, consumption, and evolution. He describes what's different in
     each of these phases, the operating models to adopt, and which cross-team
     collaboration patterns work best.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Decentralizing the Practice of Architecture at Xapo Bank]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/xapo-architecture-experience.html</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/xapo-architecture-experience.html"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T11:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's common to see a centralized architecture function that sets
     standards and oversees development projects. Such teams often suffer from
     being far removed from the issues of implementation with long
     feedback loops that slow down the flow of work. To counter these problems,
     many organizations have explored a decentralized approach to yield
     alignment between teams without these problems. One such organization is
     Xapo bank, which did this using ideas taken from Domain-Driven Design, Team
     Topologies, and the Architectural Advice Process.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stalking, not sales]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/jason/stalking-not-sales-8c750b03</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/jason/stalking-not-sales-8c750b03"/>
        <updated>2023-07-17T15:09:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What you see above is a 17-day sales sequence, or cadence. A friend of mine just sent it over and it creeped me out.
From email to LinkedIn to phone to email back to LinkedIn back to phone, and so on. I assume day 18 would be a bullhorn outside your window.
Somehow this is allowed to be called sales. But in any other realm it would be called stalking.
The sales industry calls these moments "touches", which is even creepier. And then, check out that last one: The break up email. Ouch.
Imagine if you ran this playbook when trying to sell yourself in a new relationship (or save yourself in a failing one). You meet someone new, and you contact them 15 times in a variety of ways over 17 days. And sometimes multiple times a day after they've already ignored your earlier attempts. They'd be right in calling the cops and getting a restraining order.
I know this isn't how sales always works, but it's prevalent enough. I've been on the receiving end before. It's just wrong, even if it "works" sometimes.
Clean up in aisle sales! Something's broken.

-Jason]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Fried</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rustc Trait System Refactor Initiative Update]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/07/17/trait-system-refactor-initiative.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/07/17/trait-system-refactor-initiative.html"/>
        <updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As announced in the Types Team announcement post at the start of this year, the Types Team has started to reimplement the trait solver of rustc. This refactor is similar to Chalk, but directly integrated into the existing codebase using the experience gathered over the last few years. Unlike Chalk, the new trait solver has the sole goal of replacing the existing implementation. We are separately working on formalizing the type system in a-mir-formality. It has now been half a year since that announcement which matches the first step of our roadmap.
By reimplementing the trait solver of rustc we are able to fix many subtle bugs and inefficiencies of the existing implementation. This should result in faster compilation speed and fewer bugs. The new trait solver implementation should also unb…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Inside Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Rust 1.71.0]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2023/07/13/Rust-1.71.0.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2023/07/13/Rust-1.71.0.html"/>
        <updated>2023-07-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Rust team is happy to announce a new version of Rust, 1.71.0. Rust is a programming language empowering everyone to build reliable and efficient software.
If you have a previous version of Rust installed via rustup, you can get 1.71.0 with:
rustup update stable

If you don't have it already, you can get rustup from the appropriate page on our website, and check out the detailed release notes for 1.71.0 on GitHub.
If you'd like to help us out by testing future releases, you might consider updating locally to use the beta channel (rustup default beta) or the nightly channel (rustup default nightly). Please report any bugs you might come across!
What's in 1.71.0 stable
C-unwind ABI
1.71.0 stabilizes C-unwind (and other -unwind suffixed ABI variants1).
The behavior for unforced unwinding (…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who do you do business with?]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/jason/who-do-you-do-business-with-47c6c9d5</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/jason/who-do-you-do-business-with-47c6c9d5"/>
        <updated>2023-07-12T18:16:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Way back when we launched the first version of Basecamp in 2004, we ran all our credit card charges through a merchant account provided by JP Morgan Chase.
Charging credit cards wasn't easy in the early 2000s. This was back when being an "internet company" was a major red flag. The process required mounds of paperwork, proof, and business model scrutiny just to get approved. Barely capable, ancient APIs sorta kinda let you hook into internal systems. Charging a card successfully felt like a miracle. You had no idea. It wasn't years later until companies like Stripe made it simple.
While you were never really happy with the service, you had to have it. And switching to another service meant going through the whole ungainly process again. And the grass was probably browner.
However, one day …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Fried</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We put a distributed database in the browser – and made a game of it]]></title>
        <id>http://notes.eatonphil.com/2023-07-11-we-put-a-distributed-database-in-the-browse.html</id>
        <link href="http://notes.eatonphil.com/2023-07-11-we-put-a-distributed-database-in-the-browse.html"/>
        <updated>2023-07-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is an external post of mine. Click
here
if you are not redirected.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Notes on software development</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We put a distributed database in the browser – and made a game of it]]></title>
        <id>http://notes.eatonphil.com/2023-07-11-we-put-a-distributed-database-in-the-browse.html</id>
        <link href="http://notes.eatonphil.com/2023-07-11-we-put-a-distributed-database-in-the-browse.html"/>
        <updated>2023-07-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is an external post of mine. Click
here
if you are not redirected.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Notes on software development</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You only compete with one thing]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/jason/you-only-compete-with-one-thing-48a20d93</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/jason/you-only-compete-with-one-thing-48a20d93"/>
        <updated>2023-07-10T17:24:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There's so much chatter and advice out there about how to handle "the competition".
How much should you worry about them, what you can do to beat them, how much should you pay attention to what they're doing, how you should respond when they release or say something new, what you should say when a customer compares you to them, etc.
Essentially, lots of they's and them's.
Of course you compete in a market with multiple options, but that's not your real competition.
Your real competition are your costs. Yours, not theirs. You, not them.
You ultimately stay in business when you make more money than you spend. The amount you make depends on a number of factors, many surprisingly far outside your control.
But one of the few controls you have in business is cost control. Bills don't materialize…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Fried</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let people be]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/jorge/let-people-be-52bd85a4</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/jorge/let-people-be-52bd85a4"/>
        <updated>2023-07-10T15:20:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have side-projects / don’t have them.
Do open source / don’t do it.
Have tech-related hobbies / have completely unrelated ones.
Have children / don’t have them. 
Work long hours / never put in an extra hour.
Small and risky / large and secure.
Work for others / work for yourself.
Work out of passion / work to pay the bills. 


Those are examples of dichotomies that enter my radar from time to time. Usually, someone criticizes someone else’s position after performing some intellectual judo to vilify it.


Whenever I see people telling others how to live, I can’t help wondering: isn’t figuring out what works for you already difficult enough?


Let people be.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jorge Manrubia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[1.71.0 pre-release testing]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/07/10/1.71.0-prerelease.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2023/07/10/1.71.0-prerelease.html"/>
        <updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 1.71.0 pre-release is ready for testing. The release is scheduled for
July 13. Release notes can be found here.
You can try it out locally by running:
RUSTUP_DIST_SERVER=https://dev-static.rust-lang.org rustup update stable

The index is https://dev-static.rust-lang.org/dist/2023-07-10/index.html.
You can leave feedback on the internals thread.
The release team is also thinking about changes to our pre-release process:
we'd love your feedback on this GitHub issue.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Inside Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing regex 1.9]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2023/07/05/regex-1.9.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2023/07/05/regex-1.9.html"/>
        <updated>2023-07-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The regex sub-team is announcing the release of regex 1.9. The regex crate
is maintained by the Rust project and is the recommended way to use regular
expressions in Rust. Its defining characteristic is its guarantee of worst case
linear time searches with respect to the size of the string being searched.
Releases of the regex crate aren't normally announced on this blog, but
since the majority of its internals have been rewritten in version 1.9, this
announcement serves to encourage extra scrutiny. If you run into any problems
or performance regressions, please report them on the issue tracker or ask
questions on the Discussion forum.
Few API additions have been made, but one worth calling out is the
Captures::extract method that should make getting capture groups in some
cases more convenient. Otherwise, the main change folks should see is hopefully
faster search times.
You can read more in the CHANGELOG and in a more in depth blog post on
regex crate internals as a library.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Story: A Dark Room]]></title>
        <id>ca44e4fa-443c-40a5-89be-c81013632258</id>
        <link href="https://corecursive.com/a-dark-room-with-amir-rajan/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-03T14:39:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever been frustrated with your job? Maybe not burnt out, but getting close to there? You used to love what you did, and it felt so creative and empowering, but then it starts to feel a bit more cookie cutter.
 Have you ever been frustrated with your whole life? The daily grind has taken what you love and it just doesn't feel the same anymore. Some of the magic just has slowly faded away. You don't know when it started, but it did. 
 Today's guest is Amir Rajan. He's hard to describe. 
   
 Is he a developer? Yes. An artist who sold everything that he owned for indie game development. Yes. The subject of a New Yorker profile? Yes, all of that. And also, somebody who got frustrated with his life and left everything behind.
  
Episode Page
 Support The Show
 Subscribe To The Podcast
 Join The Newsletter]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CoRecursive: Coding Stories</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social media evilness (II)]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/jorge/social-media-evilness-ii-f7f83126</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/jorge/social-media-evilness-ii-f7f83126"/>
        <updated>2023-07-02T15:43:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in the day, I wrote some notes on the puzzling question of why so many people act so maliciously toward others on social media. A book introduced me to the concept of moral outrage, which brought some answers for my questions.


A recent tweet by Dr. Jonathan Shedler referred an article that suggests a pretty different angle: the primary driver for people participating in public shaming is not justice but primarily hedonic – it makes participants feel good. A sense of justice plays a role, though: it increases the pleasure of witnessing the offender receiving punishment. I also learned a term for this form of malicious pleasure at another's misfortune: schadenfreude. This article states that the main driver for online shaming is schadenfreude.


As a completely ignorant regarding soci…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jorge Manrubia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rustfmt support for let-else statements]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2023/07/01/rustfmt-supports-let-else-statements.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2023/07/01/rustfmt-supports-let-else-statements.html"/>
        <updated>2023-07-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rustfmt will add support for formatting let-else statements starting with the nightly 2023-07-02 toolchain, and then let-else formatting support should come to stable Rust as part of the 1.72 release.
Overview
let-else statements were stabilized back in 2022 as part of the 1.65.0 release. However, the current and previous versions of Rustfmt did not have formatting support for let-else statements. When Rustfmt encountered a let-else statement it would leave it alone and maintain the manual styling originally authored by the developer.
After updating to one of the toolchains with let-else formatting support, you may notice that cargo fmt/rustfmt invocations want to "change" the formatting of your let-else statements. However, this isn't actually a "change" in formatting, but instead is simp…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rust Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The law of the land]]></title>
        <id>https://world.hey.com/dhh/the-law-of-the-land-c2231109</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/the-law-of-the-land-c2231109"/>
        <updated>2023-06-30T17:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Affirmative action is right up there with abortion and gun control among the highest-profile, longest-running social fissures in America. So of course the recent ruling from the Supreme Court making its use in college admissions illegal was going to light a political fire. The surprising thing is just how contained the burn has been within the tech industry.
But perhaps it shouldn't be so surprising. As I argued last year, we're now in the waning days of DEI's dominance within the corporate world in general and tech in particular. I don't know exactly when future historians will pin the peak, but it'll be sometime in that 2020-2021 period. The only thing that's clear today is that things have calmed down considerably since the ideological crusade reigned supreme.
Good.
It really was a craz…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>